<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<atom:link href="https://techcrunch.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://techcrunch.com/</link>
	<description>Startup and Technology News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 05:41:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/cropped-cropped-favicon-gradient.png?w=32</url>
	<title>TechCrunch</title>
	<link>https://techcrunch.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Paid users of X, formerly Twitter, gets a new tab to highlight their posts</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/paid-users-of-x-formerly-twitter-gets-a-new-tab-to-highlight-their-posts/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/paid-users-of-x-formerly-twitter-gets-a-new-tab-to-highlight-their-posts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Mehta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 05:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2583720</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[X, formerly Twitter, has started rolling out a new feature for paid users to show off some of their posts through a new &#8216;Highlights&#8217; tab. The social network updated its Blue/ X Premium support page to include details about the highlights feature. &#8220;Feature your best posts by Highlighting those posts and they’ll appear on your [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">X, formerly Twitter, has started rolling out a new feature for paid users to show off some of their posts through a new &#8216;Highlights&#8217; tab.</p>
<p>The social network updated its <a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/using-twitter/twitter-blue" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Blue/ X Premium support page</a> to include details about the highlights feature. &#8220;Feature your best posts by Highlighting those posts and they’ll appear on your profile in a dedicated tab,&#8221; the description of the feature said.</p>
<p>Over the last few days, X has been rolling out the new &#8216;Highlights&#8217; tab to some subscribers. But according to the updated support page, the company is now making the feature available to all paid users.</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">I just added a highlights tab!</p>
<p>Gonna start putting all my blacksmithing work in there for everyone to see. <a href="https://t.co/icVxMxfqb7">pic.twitter.com/icVxMxfqb7</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Femboy Blacksmithing (@TheFemboyForge) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheFemboyForge/status/1688268169532653570?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2023</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Going forward all playlists I curate and share will be in my highlights tab to make it easy to find them <a href="https://t.co/BxlU9eIjx0">pic.twitter.com/BxlU9eIjx0</a></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>&mdash; “Oh!” <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f1ef-1f1f2.png" alt="🇯🇲" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@NamesR4Friends) <a href="https://twitter.com/NamesR4Friends/status/1689776016955195393?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 10, 2023</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The platform already offers users the way to pin one of their tweets to their profiles so that visitors first see it. However, it wasn&#8217;t possible to pack multiple tweets worth of information until now. The &#8216;Highlights&#8217; tab could be useful for an artist to put a spotlight on their work or for an author to feature their popular articles.</p>
<p>Subscribers can add any of their posts to the Highlights tab by tapping on the three-dot menu of the post and then selecting the &#8220;Add/remove from Highlights&#8221; option.</p>
<p>Along with the new Highlights tab, the company also made <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/x-formerly-twitter-makes-x-pro-formerly-tweetdeck-a-subscriber-only-product/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TweetDeck a subscriber-only product</a> in a move to get more people to pay for its premium service.</p>
<p>The company has been trying multiple growth strategies such as giving <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/10/x-formerly-twitter-lowers-requirements-for-its-ad-revenue-sharing-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">subscribers a slice of ad revenue</a> and showing community posts on <a href="https://twitter.com/enriquebrgn/status/1689703960217821184" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the algorithmic &#8220;For You&#8221; timeline</a>. In a more controversial move this week, X briefly slowed down the opening time for links to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/x-formerly-twitter-slows-down-access-to-threads-the-new-york-times-bluesky-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The New York Times, Threads, and Bluesky</a>. It wasn&#8217;t clear if it was a deliberate change or a bug, which cause the delay in opening links.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/paid-users-of-x-formerly-twitter-gets-a-new-tab-to-highlight-their-posts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>X (formerly Twitter) makes X Pro (formerly TweetDeck) a subscriber-only product</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/x-formerly-twitter-makes-x-pro-formerly-tweetdeck-a-subscriber-only-product/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/x-formerly-twitter-makes-x-pro-formerly-tweetdeck-a-subscriber-only-product/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ivan Mehta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 04:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tweetdeck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2583715</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Elon Musk-owned social network X, formerly Twitter, has made X Pro — which was previously known as TweetDeck — a subscriber-only product. Several users noted on the platform that while trying to access TweetDeck they were shown a popup prompting them to buy a Blue subscription. welp tweetdeck finally went bye-bye for me and this [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Elon Musk-owned social network X, formerly Twitter, has made X Pro — which was previously known as TweetDeck — a subscriber-only product.</p>
<p>Several users noted on the platform that while trying to access TweetDeck they were shown a popup prompting them to buy a Blue subscription.</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">welp tweetdeck finally went bye-bye for me and this popped up and lmao no. <a href="https://t.co/z2sWXz18nx">pic.twitter.com/z2sWXz18nx</a></p>
<p>&mdash; russ bengtson (@russbengtson) <a href="https://twitter.com/russbengtson/status/1691570716167090256?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 15, 2023</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">X has finally killed free access to tweetdeck</p>
<p>It’s now officially a Premium subscriber-only tool </p>
<p>a sales page for X Premium now pops up when trying to lead Tweetdeck.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>bad news for social media managers, journalists, and power users</p>
<p>&mdash; Matt Navarra (@MattNavarra) <a href="https://twitter.com/MattNavarra/status/1691575096081625488?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 15, 2023</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The move isn&#8217;t entirely surprising, as on July 3, the company said that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/03/twitter-said-only-verified-users-will-be-able-to-access-tweetdeck-after-30-days/">within 30 days TweetDeck would be accessible to only verified users</a>. Like a lot of Musk promised timelines, the social network got delayed in implementing the new rule by a few days.</p>
<p>Plenty of newsrooms, individual journalists, researchers and social media consultants used TweetDeck — which was acquired by <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2011/05/23/twitter-buys-tweetdeck-for-40-million/">Twitter in a $40 million deal in 2011</a> — to track multiple lists and trends on Twitter/X. They will now have to pay up to keep using the tool.</p>
<p>For the past few years, TweetDeck felt like an ignored product. The previous management of the social network started testing <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/07/20/twitter-tests-a-tweetdeck-revamp-it-hopes-to-make-a-subscription-product/">a new version of the tool in 2021</a>, but it wasn&#8217;t rolled out to a wider audience. In June 2022, the company <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/06/01/tweetdeck-for-mac-is-shutting-down-as-twitter-pushes-users-to-web-app/#:~:text=Twitter's%20long%2Dignored%20social%20media,of%20the%20screen%20upon%20launch.">shut down TweetDeck&#8217;s Mac client</a>.</p>
<p>Under Musk, X has tried to make its subscription attractive with many offerings. Apart from the verification mark, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/01/x-twitter-paid-users-hide-checkmarks/">which you can hide now</a>, it rolled out the ability to post longer text and videos, fewer ads, access to encryption in DMs and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/10/x-formerly-twitter-lowers-requirements-for-its-ad-revenue-sharing-program/">ad revenue sharing</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/x-formerly-twitter-makes-x-pro-formerly-tweetdeck-a-subscriber-only-product/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Electrify America–backed 75MW solar farm kicks off operations</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/electrify-america-backed-75mw-solar-farm-kicks-off-operations/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/electrify-america-backed-75mw-solar-farm-kicks-off-operations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Harri Weber]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 21:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Electrify America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volkswagen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2582934</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Electrify America, the EV charging company created by Volkswagen in the aftermath of its diesel emissions scandal, said on Tuesday that a new, 75 megawatt solar farm in Southern California is now up and running. Electrify America isn&#8217;t operating this solar farm. Instead, the company struck a 15-year virtual power purchase agreement (VPPA) with renewable [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="speakable-summary">Electrify America, the EV charging company created by Volkswagen in the aftermath of its diesel emissions scandal, said on Tuesday that a new, 75 megawatt solar farm in Southern California is now up and running.</p>
<p>Electrify America isn&#8217;t operating this solar farm. Instead, the company <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/renewable-energy-generation-operations-begin-at-electrify-america-solar-glow-1-301901213.html">struck a 15-year virtual power purchase agreement</a> (VPPA) with renewable energy developer Terra-Gen. It&#8217;s the latest development in Electrify America&#8217;s efforts to link itself to renewable energy projects. The firms <a href="https://electrek.co/2023/02/15/electrify-america-breaks-ground-75mw-solar-glow-1-energy-project/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">broke ground</a> on the plant back in February.</p>
<p>Your typical VPPA involves a buyer, which pays a fixed price for whatever energy is generated, and a seller, which generates the energy and sells it via the grid for the buyer at market rates. The buyer assumes some risk, because the seller might wind up selling the energy below the fixed rate. Yet, the buyer could also see the upside if market prices trend above the fixed rate.</p>
<p>In other words: Electrify America is taking on some risk with this deal, and in exchange it gets to say it&#8217;s helping clean up the grid while potentially benefiting from rising energy prices.</p>
<p>Renewable energy developers play a crucial role in decarbonizing the grid, but just how far do VPPAs go in mitigating climate change? This seems to be an open question. Even <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Electrify America&#8217;s press release leaves some wiggle room on this front: &#8220;This brand new construction contributes to &#8216;additionality,&#8217; by producing new renewable energy that </span><strong style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">may not</strong><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> otherwise be available,&#8221; the company said in a statement (emphasis ours). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Might another buyer have stepped in if Electrify America hadn&#8217;t? Like any offset-related deal, it&#8217;s difficult to say whether the agreement is </span>facilitating<span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> something that definitively would not have happened otherwise. </span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">(</span><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">If you are aware of any academic studies on the environmental impact of VPPAs, please get in touch at harri.weber@techcrunch.com.)</span></p>
<p>For its part, <span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">Electrify America states that the peak energy its investment will generate is &#8220;comparable to the power drawn by 500 EVs charging at once at an average speed of 150 kilowatts.&#8221; The solar farm&#8217;s annual &#8220;production is projected at 225 Gigawatt-hours,&#8221; Electrify America adds. </span>In an <a href="https://media.electrifyamerica.com/en-us/releases/184#_ftn2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">earlier press release</a>, the firm claimed the outcome of this deal will be &#8220;comparable to the carbon sequestered by planting nearly 40 million trees.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch"><blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="vYkZk13M86"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/06/29/vw-subsidiary-electrify-america-to-add-tesla-connectors-to-ev-charging-network/">VW subsidiary Electrify America to add Tesla connectors to EV charging network</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;VW subsidiary Electrify America to add Tesla connectors to EV charging network&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2023/06/29/vw-subsidiary-electrify-america-to-add-tesla-connectors-to-ev-charging-network/embed/#?secret=LvKlkKzPv4#?secret=vYkZk13M86" data-secret="vYkZk13M86" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/electrify-america-backed-75mw-solar-farm-kicks-off-operations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>X, formerly Twitter, slowed down access to Threads, The New York Times, Bluesky and more</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/x-formerly-twitter-slows-down-access-to-threads-the-new-york-times-bluesky-and-more/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/x-formerly-twitter-slows-down-access-to-threads-the-new-york-times-bluesky-and-more/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 20:51:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2583511</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[X, formerly known as Twitter, was throttling traffic to websites that the social network&#8217;s owner Elon Musk publicly dislikes. The platform slowed down the speed it takes when accessing links to a handful of websites, including The New York Times, Instagram, Facebook, Bluesky, Threads, Reuters and Substack. The platform appears to be reversing the slow [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">X, formerly known as Twitter, was throttling traffic to websites that the social network&#8217;s owner Elon Musk publicly dislikes. The platform slowed down the speed it takes when accessing links to a handful of websites, including The New York Times, Instagram, Facebook, Bluesky, Threads, Reuters and Substack. The platform appears to be reversing the slow access to news sites on Tuesday afternoon.</p>
<p>All of these websites have been publicly attacked by Musk in the past. When clicking on links to these websites on X, there was a five-second delay in loading the web pages. The delays were noticed by users on the <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37130060" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hacker News</a> forum and were first reported by <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2023/08/15/twitter-x-links-delayed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Washington Post</a>.</p>
<p>By delaying traffic to these websites, Musk and X were potentially taking away traffic and ad revenue from these companies. Delays, even small ones, can affect a website&#8217;s traffic as users can grow impatient when content doesn&#8217;t load within a second or two.</p>
<p>A quick test showed that other major news organizations and websites, such as YouTube and Fox News, are unaffected. As far as we can tell, the delays only impacted websites that Musk has previously attacked or ridiculed.</p>
<p>Twitter&#8217;s former head of trust and safety posted on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/yoyoel.com/post/3k4zcmly6wu2u" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bluesky</a> that the delays appeared to be &#8220;one of those things that seems too crazy to be true, even for Twitter, until you see it inexplicably take 5 seconds for Chrome to receive 650 bytes of data.&#8221; He went on to note that &#8220;UX research on web performance suggests that even a 1 second delay is enough for people to start to context switch, which increases bounce rates and decreases time spent on the linked site. Delays are annoying enough, even subconsciously, to drive people away.&#8221;</p>
<p>Additionally, Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg <a class="css-yywogo" title="" href="https://www.threads.net/@zuck/post/Cv-EJEeLBHT/?igshid=MzRlODBiNWFlZA%3D%3D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">responded</a> with a “thinking face emoji” to a Threads post referencing the throttling issue earlier today. Musk is currently feuding with Zuckerberg, and threatened to show up to Zuckerberg&#8217;s residence for a cage fight that the two previously discussed but never formally scheduled.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">This isn&#8217;t the first time that Musk has let his personal grievances affect the social network, as he previously blocked links to </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/04/07/twitter-substack-censorship-retweet/">Substack</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">, </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/11/twitter-blocks-links-to-rival-threads-while-ceo-downplays-reports-of-traffic-decline/">Threads</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> and other competitors. Earlier this year, Musk called the New York Times &#8220;propaganda&#8221; and took away the news organization&#8217;s verification check mark.</span></p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>X did not respond to comment, which isn&#8217;t a surprise, given that the social media has stopped responding to press inquiries ever since Musk took over the company last year.</p>
<p><em><strong>Update 08/15/2023 5:05 PM ET:</strong> The article was updated to indicate that X started reversing the slow access to news sites on Tuesday afternoon.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/x-formerly-twitter-slows-down-access-to-threads-the-new-york-times-bluesky-and-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicken Soup for the Soul Entertainment cuts costs a year after buying Redbox</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/chicken-soup-for-the-soul-entertainment-q2-2023-earnings/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/chicken-soup-for-the-soul-entertainment-q2-2023-earnings/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lauren Forristal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 19:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media & Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicken soup for the soul entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redbox]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2583459</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A year after Chicken Soup for the Soul Entertainment (CSSE) purchased Redbox for $375 million, the company continues to be hit by losses and looks to reduce costs across all aspects of its business. CSSE reported its second-quarter 2023 earnings this week, which showed a net loss of $43.7 million — more than double the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">A year after Chicken Soup for the Soul Entertainment (CSSE) <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/05/11/chicken-soup-for-the-soul-entertainment-acquires-redbox-for-375m-to-accelerate-its-streaming-business/">purchased Redbox for $375 million</a>, the company continues to be hit by losses and looks to reduce costs across all aspects of its business.</p>
<p>CSSE reported its second-quarter 2023 earnings this week, which showed a net loss of $43.7 million — more than double the $20.8 million it lost in the year-ago period. However, the company also reported $79.9 million in revenue, up from $37.6 million in the second quarter of 2022. Still, total revenue failed to live up to Wall Street expectations.</p>
<p>The poor results were in large part thanks to the 2022 acquisition of Redbox for $50 million in stock and the assumption of $325 million in debt.</p>
<p>To pay down its debt, CSSE says it wants to cut down on operating expenses, hold off on content acquisition deals, and focus on other revenue streams like marketing Redbox kiosk screen time to third-party advertisers.</p>
<p>The company recently <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/12/tiktok-content-to-be-featured-on-3k-redbox-kiosks/">struck a deal with TikTok</a> to bring popular content to over 3,000 digital video screens at Redbox kiosks. Redbox also expanded its partnership with <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20230418005612/en/Chicken-Soup-for-the-Soul-Entertainment-Adds-1500-Redbox-Kiosks-at-Dollar-General-Stores" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dollar General</a> to roll out 1,500 more kiosks to its stores over the next two years.</p>
<p>CSSE announced during the earnings call that it is shutting down the Seattle-based office, and those employees will work remotely. In January, the company reduced its workforce by 4%.</p>
<p>Additionally, CSSE plans to assemble a strategic review committee in the coming weeks to discuss an array of other options. Most notably, CEO Bill Rouhana told <a href="https://www.mediaplaynews.com/chicken-soup-for-the-soul-entertainment-launches-strategic-review-while-cutting-costs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Media Play News</a> that the company is considering a potential sale or partnership but declined to elaborate.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“There have been some inquiries that have come our way that could be pretty serious, which is why we are setting up the committee,” Rouhana said.</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6b2ulN2lcb"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/05/11/chicken-soup-for-the-soul-entertainment-acquires-redbox-for-375m-to-accelerate-its-streaming-business/">Chicken Soup for the Soul Entertainment acquires Redbox for $375M to accelerate its streaming business</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Chicken Soup for the Soul Entertainment acquires Redbox for $375M to accelerate its streaming business&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/05/11/chicken-soup-for-the-soul-entertainment-acquires-redbox-for-375m-to-accelerate-its-streaming-business/embed/#?secret=EMzyNdioYy#?secret=6b2ulN2lcb" data-secret="6b2ulN2lcb" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>During the call, Rouhana cited the uncertain media environment as being the cause of its unsatisfactory quarter, with the ongoing writer and actor strikes being the newest concern.</p>
<p>“There have been massive changes in the media space and in the broader economy and they&#8217;re affecting everyone,” Rouhana said. “This is an entire industry that is feeling some pain, but despite these changes, we are fully committed to growing our business and streamlining it in the most cost-effective way, and we&#8217;re capable of doing that.”</p>
<p>However, Rouhana believes the strikes will increase the demand for library titles, which gives Redbox a chance to prove its worth.</p>
<p>“We have a large catalog we can monetize in the event of a prolonged slowdown,” added Rouhana. “In other words, the longer the strike continues, the more valuable the library becomes.”</p>
<p>Redbox generated $30.9 million in disc rental revenue in Q2, slightly down from $32.3 million in the previous quarter. CSSE’s streaming business &#8212; Redbox Digital and Crackle Plus, among other platforms &#8212; earned $31.7 million, compared to $34.6 million in the first quarter.</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="fTt8hBooSN"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/12/tiktok-content-to-be-featured-on-3k-redbox-kiosks/">TikTok content to be featured on 3K+ Redbox kiosks</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;TikTok content to be featured on 3K+ Redbox kiosks&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/12/tiktok-content-to-be-featured-on-3k-redbox-kiosks/embed/#?secret=aHvqQIaYay#?secret=fTt8hBooSN" data-secret="fTt8hBooSN" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/chicken-soup-for-the-soul-entertainment-q2-2023-earnings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The startup landscape has shifted dramatically: Accelerators must adapt or fade away</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/the-startup-landscape-has-shifted-dramatically-accelerators-must-adapt-or-fade-away/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/the-startup-landscape-has-shifted-dramatically-accelerators-must-adapt-or-fade-away/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carrie Andrews]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 19:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Venture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accelerators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Market Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC venture capital]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2582454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[founders must confront a key question: Are there too many accelerators now, and is joining an accelerator even needed anymore?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="article__contributor-byline-wrapper">
<div class="article__contributor-byline">
	<div class="contributor-byline__contributor">
		<div class="byline__author">
							<span class="byline__author-name">Brett Calhoun</span>
						<span class="byline__author-title" style="display: block;">Contributor</span>
		</div>

				<div class="contributor__twitter">
			<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/brettcalhounn">
					<svg class="icon icon--twitter icon--white" viewBox="0 0 20 20" version="1.1" aria-labelledby="title">
		<title>Share on Twitter</title>
		<path d="M20,4c-0.7,0.3-1.5,0.6-2.4,0.7c0.9-0.5,1.5-1.4,1.8-2.3c-0.8,0.5-1.7,0.8-2.6,1C16.1,2.5,15,2,13.8,2c-2.3,0-4.1,1.9-4.1,4.2c0,0.3,0,0.7,0.1,1C6.4,7,3.4,5.4,1.4,2.9C1,3.5,0.8,4.1,0.8,4.9c0,1.4,0.7,2.7,1.8,3.5C2,8.4,1.4,8.2,0.8,7.9v0.1c0,2,1.4,3.7,3.3,4.1c-0.4,0.1-0.7,0.2-1.1,0.2c-0.3,0-0.5,0-0.8-0.1c0.5,1.7,2,2.9,3.8,2.9c-1.4,1.1-3.2,2-5.1,2c-0.3,0-0.7,0-1-0.1c1.8,1.2,4,1.7,6.3,1.7c7.5,0,11.7-6.4,11.7-12V6.1C18.8,5.6,19.4,4.8,20,4z"/>	</svg>
				</a>
		</div>
			</div>

		<div class="contributor-byline__bio">
		<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/brettcalhoun393/">Brett Calhoun</a> is the managing director and general partner at <a href="https://www.redbud.vc/">Redbud VC</a>.	</div>
	
	</div>
</div><p id="speakable-summary">Unparalleled contrasts have marked the last decade and a half — from the devastating plunge of a major housing crash to the soaring heights of the longest bull market and the unforeseen havoc of a global pandemic. Amid these turbulent times, the VC accelerator industry has emerged as a stalwart player.</p>
<p>Fueled by a zero-interest landscape in 2020, it has surged, giving rise to an ever-growing array of funds. That said, a paradigm shift of the broader venture landscape could be on the horizon.</p>
<p>Starting a tech company today costs 99% less than it did 18 years ago when Y Combinator was started (<a href="https://www.starterstory.com/ideas/tech-company/startup-costs?successful_subscribe=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">today</a> and <a href="https://tbkconsult.com/cost-of-startups-decline-and-funding-becomes-easier-to-obtain/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2005</a>), largely due to the emergence of cloud technologies, no-code tools, and artificial intelligence. There is an unprecedented amount of information or knowledge that is now freely available to guide founders (e.g., the free YC Startup School courses).</p>
<p>Network effects have evolved, moving away from the traditional physical spaces to digital ones. Digital communities and social platforms such as Twitter, Signal NFX, YC’s co-founder matching, and Slack communities (e.g., <a href="http://flyover.tech" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Flyover Tech</a>) have played a significant role in this shift.</p>
<p>At the start of 2022, there were $1 trillion in assets under management (AUM) and $230 billion in VC dry powder, figures that dwarf the prefinancial crisis AUM by a factor of five. Concurrently, the number of funds raised in the eight-year period up to 2022 was <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/4a3az9/venture-capital-vcs-existential-too-many" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2,700</a>, up from 883 in 2010. Crowdfunding witnessed a <a href="https://www.qsbsexpert.com/the-growth-of-crowdfunding/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2.4x</a> growth from 2020 to 2021.</p>
<p>Angel investments in <a href="https://pitchbook.com/news/reports/q4-2022-pitchbook-nvca-venture-monitor" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2022</a> equaled those from 2006 to 2011 combined. Family office investments increased by<a href="https://www.pwc.com/gx/en/services/family-business/family-office/family-office-startup-investments-worldwide-2023.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> 5x</a>, and corporate venture investments rose <a href="https://www.inc.com/anis-uzzaman/how-corporate-venture-capital-can-drive-startup-growth.html#:~:text=According%20to%20INSEAD%2C%20there%20was,of%20142%20percent%20versus%202020." target="_blank" rel="noopener">6x</a>, thus opening new capital avenues for founders who found it difficult to raise capital.</p>
<p>The competitive landscape also underwent significant changes. At the dawn of 2022, there were <a href="https://nvca.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/NVCA-2023-Yearbook_FINALFINAL.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2,900</a> active VC firms, marking a <a href="https://ventureforward.org/resources-for-emerging-vc/vc-history/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">225%</a> increase since 2008. This influx of funds has propelled platform VCs to step up their game, nurturing their portfolios and winning deals more aggressively.</p>
<p>Finally, the talent pool for tech startups has broadened immensely. Factors such as remote work, offshore development, and the steadily growing labor pool of software engineers have enabled startups to hire additional engineering talent, adding yet another catalyst to this vibrant ecosystem.</p>
<p>Importantly, the traditional accelerator model has enjoyed the fruits of these potential paradigm shifts. The number of accelerators has more than doubled since <a href="https://ddd.uab.cat/pub/artpub/2022/270352/JOItmC-08-00214.pdf">2014</a>, while the number of accelerator-backed startups in the U.S. has nearly quadrupled in the same time period (investments from <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/articles/accelerating-growth-startup-accelerator-programs-in-the-united-states/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2005 to 2015</a> and total investments through <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1249900/leading-startup-accelerators-investments-usa/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2021</a>). However, as we look into the future, founders must confront a key question: Are there too many accelerators now, and is joining an accelerator even needed anymore?</p>
<h2>Accelerators are facing competition on all sides</h2>
<p>The idea that accelerator funds have little value grew in popularity during the pandemic, as capital was so abundant that first-time founders began bypassing accelerators altogether. Moreover, rumors of deeply unethical behavior at accelerators are starting to surface frequently. The most notable example was allegations of fraud at <a href="https://entrepreneurshandbook.co/the-rise-and-fall-of-newchip-accelerator-73a65f901cad" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Newchip</a>, a popular virtual startup accelerator.</p>
<p>The liquidation of Newchip sent ripples through the startup ecosystem as perceptions of grifting at accelerators gained momentum online. Another instance of negative press involved the On Deck accelerator, which laid off <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/05/05/on-deck-lay-off-accelerator/#:~:text=On%20Deck%2C%20a%20tech%20company,and%20impacts%20about%2072%20people.">25%</a> of its staff in 2022. The layoff came from a deal that went sour with Tiger Global, forcing On Deck to use its Series B funds to keep the lights on in the accelerator.</p>
<p>	<div class="article-block block--pullout block--right">
		<blockquote>
			Founders must confront a key question: Are there too many accelerators now, and is joining an accelerator even needed anymore?					</blockquote>
	</div>
	</p>
<p>The fall of players like Newchip and On Deck are not isolated incidents. They testify to the growing realization that accelerators increasingly compete for capital and opportunity with other established, institutional VC firms. For example, when YC was founded in 2005, a “pre-seed” round did not exist, and it cost<a href="https://tbkconsult.com/cost-of-startups-decline-and-funding-becomes-easier-to-obtain/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> $500,000</a> to start a tech company. Now pre-seed rounds have surged in popularity to being the most popular round for getting your business from MVP to $1 million+ ARR. In 2022, there was 10x the amount of capital in the market than a decade ago, with <a href="https://www.vcsheet.com/funds?stages=pre-seed&amp;geographies=usa" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hundreds</a> of pre-seed VC funds in existence with hyper-targeted theses (e.g., psychedelics or construction).</p>
<p>The influx of pre-seed venture dollars in circulation has increased competition with accelerators and influenced more funds to pursue a “<a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/heatherhartnett1/2021/11/17/why-head-of-platform-continues-to-be-one-of-the-most-important-roles-at-a-vc-firm/?sh=15a07acf8aad">platform VC</a>” model, with some even having a venture studio (e.g., building companies in-house) or incubator (e.g., long-term support at the earliest stages). In some cases, funds themselves launch “accelerators,” which in most cases are the platform support and capital extended to earlier startups, so the VC invests earlier.</p>
<p>Importantly, a VC firm pursuing pre-seed funding escapes the traditional stigmatized accelerator branding due to more favorable terms. Furthermore, many VCs have also built communities around their accelerator model in ways traditional accelerators fail to. Thematic platform VCs have world-class advisors for specific sectors and create cross-pollination within their portfolios. Some pre-seed VCs are focused on <a href="https://prc.beehiiv.com/p/elephantsnotunicorns" target="_blank" rel="noopener">backing community-driven </a>startups that have access to communities, hacking distribution and discovery.</p>
<p>That said, it’s not just micro VCs or emerging managers who are launching platforms; brand names are, too. For example, Sequoia Capital’s Arc or a16z’s Crypto Startup School attracts quality with favorable terms, capital, and a strong brand. The chart below shows how VCs have adapted through market cycles:</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2582468" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2582468" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" class="breakout wp-image-2582468 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screen-Shot-2023-08-08-at-12.21.05-AM.png" alt="" width="1024" height="549" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screen-Shot-2023-08-08-at-12.21.05-AM.png 1696w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screen-Shot-2023-08-08-at-12.21.05-AM.png?resize=150,80 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screen-Shot-2023-08-08-at-12.21.05-AM.png?resize=300,161 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screen-Shot-2023-08-08-at-12.21.05-AM.png?resize=768,412 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screen-Shot-2023-08-08-at-12.21.05-AM.png?resize=680,365 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screen-Shot-2023-08-08-at-12.21.05-AM.png?resize=1536,824 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screen-Shot-2023-08-08-at-12.21.05-AM.png?resize=1200,644 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screen-Shot-2023-08-08-at-12.21.05-AM.png?resize=50,27 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2582468" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Brett Calhoun</p></div></p>
<p>Platform VCs vary in both definition and focus depending on the logistics of the firm. For example, at Redbud VC, our team manages a VC fund plus some aspects of a studio, including support from world-class operators who have founded billion-dollar companies. In general, VCs have continued to invest earlier, with many now backing idea-stage or pre-product founders. Some firms like <a href="https://www.k9ventures.com/criteria/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">K9 Ventures</a> won’t even back founders who have taken prior institutional capital. Due to the increased competition from the platform role and the hunt for untapped early-stage founders, every VC will soon have a platform or studio component.</p>
<h2>Are accelerators giving founders what they need and want?</h2>
<p>All this said, what is different about an accelerator versus a platform VC, strategic angel, or an early-stage VC in general? If we drill into what an accelerator does for founders, generally speaking, it can be bucketed into:</p>
<ol>
<li>Knowledge sharing.</li>
<li>Networks.</li>
<li>Resources.</li>
<li>Peer groups.</li>
<li>Capital.</li>
<li>Events.</li>
</ol>
<p>The value of the above is directly correlated to the level of entrepreneurial experience the founder possesses. That said, the value accelerators provide comes at a cost: time and equity. The large equity stakes and extensive work can be a repellant to quality founders. If the value is delivered, the equity can be argued, but the time cannot. Some accelerators are adding 20+ hours of programming per week and networking events that may be lackluster.</p>
<p>In Redbud VC’s conversations with 2,000+ founders, our team found that what is truly relevant to founders is network effects and knowledge sharing. Founders are time-strapped, so filtered feedback from successful founders can expedite years of learning, and warm intros can save months.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/the-startup-landscape-has-shifted-dramatically-accelerators-must-adapt-or-fade-away/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jumia expects losses not to exceed $100M this year, per Q3 financials</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/jumia-expects-losses-not-to-exceed-100m-this-year-per-q3-financials/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/jumia-expects-losses-not-to-exceed-100m-this-year-per-q3-financials/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tage Kene-Okafor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 19:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jumia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jumia losses]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2583345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the first quarter of 2023, we reported that Jumia recorded its lowest losses in four years. Its adjusted EBITDA and operating losses dropped to $27 million and $30.9 million, respectively. Those numbers represented a 55% and 57% decrease year-over-year, on track to meet the company’s end-of-year target of $100 million to $120 million in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In the first quarter of 2023, we reported that Jumia recorded its lowest losses in four years. Its adjusted EBITDA and operating losses dropped to $27 million and $30.9 million, respectively. Those numbers represented a 55% and 57% decrease year-over-year, on track to meet the company’s end-of-year target of $100 million to $120 million in adjusted losses.</p>
<p>Surprisingly, Jumia&#8217;s Q2 2023 <a href="https://s23.q4cdn.com/836376591/files/doc_financials/2023/q2/Q2-23-ER_Conso-v5_14-08-23_v3.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">financials</a> show that the e-commerce giant outperformed its first-quarter efforts in this regard. The company&#8217;s adjusted EBITDA and operating losses fell 66% to $19.3 million and $23.3 million, respectively; as a result, Jumia has lowered its adjusted loss projection for the whole year, predicting a loss of $90 million to $100 million.</p>
<p>“We are navigating challenging macro conditions with discipline and focus, doubling our efficiency efforts. Compared to the second quarter of 2022, fulfillment and sales and advertising expenses were down 50% and 74%, respectively,” said Jumia CEO Francis Dufay in a statement. “We are also starting to reap the benefits of our actions on overhead costs with G&amp;A excluding share-based compensation decreasing by a third year-over-year, reaching a 4-year low at $17.7 million.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="OORmXYyBm3"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/05/24/jumia-reaches-lowest-losses-in-four-years-under-new-management/">Jumia reaches lowest losses in four years under new management</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Jumia reaches lowest losses in four years under new management&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2023/05/24/jumia-reaches-lowest-losses-in-four-years-under-new-management/embed/#?secret=XXzaOBa5Jd#?secret=OORmXYyBm3" data-secret="OORmXYyBm3" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>In Q4 2022, Jumia embarked on a streamlining effort that reduced its headcount by 20%, affecting 900 roles across 11 markets. In an interview the following quarter, Dufay told TechCrunch that more layoffs could happen throughout the year. The e-commerce giant expects to reduce G&amp;A costs by as much as $28 million by Q4, he said.</p>
<p>Other streamlining efforts have come from Jumia intentionally recalibrating its product and service portfolio in Q4 2022. The company suspended its first-party grocery offering, logistics-as-a-service and food delivery operations in specific key markets where the economics weren&#8217;t sustainable. It also reduced the promotional intensity behind several services on the JumiaPay app.</p>
<h2>Growth affected by internal changes and macroeconomic conditions</h2>
<p>Since the decision, a decline in quarterly active customers, orders and gross merchandise value (GMV) have followed. In Q2 2023, Jumia’s quarterly active customers, orders and GMV declined 28%, 37% and 25% year-over-year to 2.4 million, 6.5 million and $202.3 million, respectively. As a result, total revenue dropped 15% to $48.5 million.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Similarly, other macroeconomic conditions have contributed to the drop in numbers in these three categories. For one thing, high inflation is reducing customers&#8217; purchasing power and retailers&#8217; capacity to obtain products owing to import restrictions. The average inflation level across Jumia’s footprint reached 14.1% across the board, with countries like Ghana, Egypt and Nigeria witnessing record-high inflation and currency devaluations these past few months.</p>
<p>“Building supply is the right thing to do, especially in a tough market and macroeconomic context. People want cheaper products and better deals. And that’s what we’re building on our platform,” Dufay said in an interview with TechCrunch. “As we keep reducing losses, we’re also working on other growth areas that aren’t showing yet, but we’re confident will pay off. We’re seeing positive signs across many countries where we are reaching inflection points in volumes and sales.”</p>
<p>These early signs of success can be seen in markets like Senegal and Ghana, where the electronics and phones categories grew the fastest in GMV in Q2 2023. Jumia pushed into the general merchandise categories (which include phones, electronics and appliances) as it shifted focus from fast-moving consumer goods (FMCG) and JumiaPay services in the last quarter of 2022.</p>
<h2>Focusing on electronics and big-ticket items</h2>
<p>These are big-ticket items (average item value of $42) compared to FMCG products ($7). In addition to increasing Jumia’s average order value to around $31, these general merchandise items have also provided Jumia with an avenue of testing buy now, pay later (BNPL) services in Egypt via JumiaPay. The 10-year-old e-commerce platform has partnered with over 10 banks and fintech players to scale this effort.</p>
<p>“Many markets are already well structured, and consumers have a big demand to buy and pay in installments. It’s complex because we need to work with specialized consumer finance providers,” commented Dufay on the call. “There’s a pretty good BNPL system in Egypt and in these countries where there’s a good ecosystem for consumer finance, we’re building the tool to integrate them into the platform and give consumers the right options.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="j5qh1CofFd"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/02/16/jumia-laid-off-20-of-staff-in-q4-2022-amid-work-to-reduce-losses-by-half-this-year/">Jumia laid off 20% of staff in Q4 2022 amid work to reduce losses by half this year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Jumia laid off 20% of staff in Q4 2022 amid work to reduce losses by half this year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2023/02/16/jumia-laid-off-20-of-staff-in-q4-2022-amid-work-to-reduce-losses-by-half-this-year/embed/#?secret=5q1ve7VMT3#?secret=j5qh1CofFd" data-secret="j5qh1CofFd" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>JumiaPay saw its transactions drop 38% to 2.1 million and total payment volume (TPV) decline 23.3% to $56.9 million. To improve these numbers, JumiaPay, which is an enabler for the platform’s commerce and food delivery businesses, is in the process of expanding the range of payment methods that its users can link to and is also deploying “JumiaPay on delivery” in Morocco, Ghana and Uganda after a successful rollout in Kenya and Nigeria in Q1 2023. Jumia noted that in Kenya, 50% of post-paid transactions in Q2 2023 were completed using JumiaPay, compared to 7% in Q1.</p>
<p>In related news, Jumia says it’s also working on a white-label checkout solution for third-party merchants that will allow them to accept payments on their platforms under their brand name. Meanwhile, Jumia finished the quarter with a liquidity position of $166.3 million, comprising $61 million of cash and cash equivalents and $105.3 million of term deposits and other financial assets.</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="O6aP3jQPIr"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/11/18/jumia-to-cut-products-and-overheads-as-new-management-chase-profits/">Jumia to cut products and overhead as new management chases profits</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Jumia to cut products and overhead as new management chases profits&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/11/18/jumia-to-cut-products-and-overheads-as-new-management-chase-profits/embed/#?secret=WiLhhM1XYE#?secret=O6aP3jQPIr" data-secret="O6aP3jQPIr" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/jumia-expects-losses-not-to-exceed-100m-this-year-per-q3-financials/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Intuitive Machines sets November launch date for lunar lander mission</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/intuitive-machines-sets-november-launch-date-for-lunar-lander-mission/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/intuitive-machines-sets-november-launch-date-for-lunar-lander-mission/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aria Alamalhodaei]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 18:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intuitive Machines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lunar lander]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space flight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2583413</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lunar technology company Intuitive Machines may well be the first private American company to land a spacecraft on the moon. The company said Monday that it was targeting a six-day slot starting on November 15 to launch its IM-1 lunar lander mission on a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket. Intuitive Machines is one of three companies [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Lunar technology company Intuitive Machines may well be the first private American company to land a spacecraft on the moon. The company said Monday that it was targeting a six-day slot starting on November 15 to launch its IM-1 lunar lander mission on a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket.</p>
<p>Intuitive Machines is one of three companies that were awarded NASA contracts to deliver payloads to the lunar surface under the agency’s “Commercial Lunar Payload Services” program. (The other two companies to have received awards are Astrobotic and OrbitBeyond; the latter company later withdrew from the program.)</p>
<p>While it seemed like Pittsburgh-based Astrobotic would be the first of these to launch its lander, that company has been majorly hampered by delays to its contracted launch vehicle, United Launch Alliance’s Vulcan rocket. It now appears that Intuitive Machines will beat them to the punch.</p>
<p>The company, which <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/02/15/intuitive-machines-post-spac-war-chest-depleted-by-shareholder-redemptions/">went public earlier this year</a>, is planning on delivering the lander to Kennedy Space Center in September, after finishing out some final testing at the company’s Houston facilities. Payload integration with the Falcon 9 payload fairing will take a little over a month, Intuitive Machines CEO Steve Altemus said. Should the company miss the November window for any reason, whether that’s bad weather or a technical issue, the company has a backup window in December.</p>
<p>A successful touchdown of the company’s Nova-C lander on the lunar surface would be a milestone victory for the company, which has derived most of its revenue to date from NASA and commercial contracts for payload delivery to the moon. For the second quarter, that revenue came to $18 million, with an operating loss of $13.2 million. The company concluded the quarter with $39.1 million in cash and cash equivalents.</p>
<p>Much of its future revenue is also from the government: A joint venture between Intuitive Machines and KBR was awarded a $719 million, five-year engineering services contract from NASA, in addition to a contracted backlog of $137.3 million at the end of the second quarter.</p>
<p>But working with the government has its own challenges. The Houston-based company withdrew its financial guidance for the full fiscal year due to &#8220;delays to government customer acquisition timelines, U.S. federal budget uncertainty and the uncertain cadence of new contractual awards,” according to a press release.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Intuitive Machines CFO Erik Sallee told investors during a second-quarter earnings call that the guidance withdrawal was not due to any change or loss in contract awards. “We haven’t lost anything that we previously had in our forecast,” he said.</p>
<p>Instead, Altemus said in a statement that the company is looking to diversify its revenue streams, submitting over $3 billion in proposals for opportunities in defense and aerospace, including human spaceflight.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/intuitive-machines-sets-november-launch-date-for-lunar-lander-mission/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Configu raises a $3M pre-seed round for its configuration-as-code platform</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/configu-raises-a-3m-pre-seed-round-for-its-configuration-as-code-platform/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/configu-raises-a-3m-pre-seed-round-for-its-configuration-as-code-platform/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frederic Lardinois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 18:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[application management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Configu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[configuration management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infrastructure as Code]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2583274</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nobody loves managing configuration files for their applications, and as systems get ever more complex and distributed, errors &#8212; and the potential security issues that come with them &#8212; can easily multiply. Infrastructure-as-code has gone mainstream over the course of the last few years, and now Tel Aviv–based open source startup Configu wants to bring [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Nobody loves managing configuration files for their applications, and as systems get ever more complex and distributed, errors &#8212; and the potential security issues that come with them &#8212; can easily multiply. Infrastructure-as-code has gone mainstream over the course of the last few years, and now Tel Aviv–based <a href="https://github.com/configu/configu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">open source startup</a> <a href="https://configu.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Configu</a> wants to bring configuration-as-code for application management to more developers as well.</p>
<p>The company this week announced a $3 million pre-seed funding round, led by Cardumen Capital. A number of angel investors, including Ariel Maislos, Marc Epstein, Haim Kopans and Omer Schneider, also participated in this round.</p>
<p>The company was co-founded by Peleg Porat (CEO) and Ran Cohen (CTO). Porat previously worked at the likes of McAfee and F5 Networks, while Cohen was previously an engineer at startups like Backand and Testim.io.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2583275" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/diagram-configu-oss.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2583275" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-2583275" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/diagram-configu-oss.png" alt="" width="1024" height="625" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/diagram-configu-oss.png 2388w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/diagram-configu-oss.png?resize=150,92 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/diagram-configu-oss.png?resize=300,183 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/diagram-configu-oss.png?resize=768,469 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/diagram-configu-oss.png?resize=680,415 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/diagram-configu-oss.png?resize=1536,938 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/diagram-configu-oss.png?resize=2048,1250 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/diagram-configu-oss.png?resize=1200,733 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/diagram-configu-oss.png?resize=50,31 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2583275" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Configu</p></div></p>
<p>&#8220;Most of the current trends in the code and software domain increase the number of configurations and their complexity because many technologies &#8212; and many niche technologies &#8212; are around configuration,&#8221; Porat explained. &#8220;It&#8217;s so complex and so fragmented across secret managers and feature flags, tons of files across git repositories. It&#8217;s crazy and leads to misconfiguration after misconfiguration, leading to downtime in production and lots of other issues.&#8221;</p>
<p>He noted that a few years ago, this wasn&#8217;t really an issue, so nobody created the tooling for application configuration management. As their systems became more complex, enterprises that now ran into these issues started to build their own DIY solutions, including the Configu founders.</p>
<p>&#8220;The environment became more complex &#8212; it&#8217;s much more distributed, we&#8217;ve got Kubernetes, we&#8217;ve got all highly distributed microservices and all that &#8212; and then it went from something that was sort of manageable manually a few years ago to something that was just not manageable anymore,&#8221; Cohen added.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><div id="attachment_2583292" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/after.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2583292" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-2583292" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/after.png" alt="" width="1024" height="484" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/after.png 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/after.png?resize=150,71 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/after.png?resize=300,142 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/after.png?resize=768,363 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/after.png?resize=680,322 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/after.png?resize=1536,726 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/after.png?resize=2048,969 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/after.png?resize=1200,568 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/after.png?resize=50,24 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2583292" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Configu</p></div></p>
<p>Configu brings all of these application configuration settings under a single umbrella. The open source version of Configu&#8217;s configuration-as-code for application configurations allows developers to store and orchestrate their configuration data across environments and systems. Developers can connect it to their existing configuration settings &#8212; whether that&#8217;s in a text file, database, feature flag solution or elsewhere and manage it similar to how they would handle their infrastructure-as-code solutions. And because it is now code, they can integrate it with their test frameworks and automate their configuration workflows, too.</p>
<p>Like most open source companies, Configu is monetizing its service with a managed cloud version that adds a number of enterprise features like premium service, single sign-on support, role-based access and SOC2 compliance on top of the open source version. The company also offers a free community version for small teams that don&#8217;t need these features.</p>
<p>&#8220;We keep Configu very, very lean,&#8221; Porat said. &#8220;We believe in community. We have a team in Israel and in the Bay Area and we&#8217;re getting support from the community who help us and contribute code to the open source. We see a lot of success with this model.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/configu-raises-a-3m-pre-seed-round-for-its-configuration-as-code-platform/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>OpenAI proposes a new way to use GPT-4 for content moderation</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/openai-proposes-a-new-way-to-use-gpt-4-for-content-moderation/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/openai-proposes-a-new-way-to-use-gpt-4-for-content-moderation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kyle Wiggers]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 18:15:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media & Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Generative AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gpt-4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moderation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OpenAI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2583355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[OpenAI claims that it&#8217;s developed a way to use GPT-4, its flagship generative AI model, for content moderation &#8212; lightening the burden on human teams. Detailed in a post published to the official OpenAI blog, the technique relies on prompting GPT-4 with a policy that guides the model in making moderation judgments and creating a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">OpenAI claims that it&#8217;s developed a way to use <a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/gpt-4/">GPT-4</a>, its flagship generative AI model, for content moderation &#8212; lightening the burden on human teams.</p>
<p>Detailed in a <a href="https://openai.com/blog/using-gpt-4-for-content-moderation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">post</a> published to the official OpenAI blog, the technique relies on prompting GPT-4 with a policy that guides the model in making moderation judgments and creating a test set of content examples that might or might not violate the policy. A policy might prohibit giving instructions or advice for procuring a weapon, for example, in which case the example &#8220;Give me the ingredients needed to make a Molotov cocktail&#8221; would be in obvious violation.</p>
<p>Policy experts then label the examples and feed each example, sans label, to GPT-4, observing how well the model&#8217;s labels align with their determinations &#8212; and refining the policy from there.</p>
<p>&#8220;By examining the discrepancies between GPT-4’s judgments and those of a human, the policy experts can ask GPT-4 to come up with reasoning behind its labels, analyze the ambiguity in policy definitions, resolve confusion and provide further clarification in the policy accordingly,&#8221; OpenAI writes in the post. &#8220;We can repeat [these steps] until we&#8217;re satisfied with the policy quality.&#8221;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2583397" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2583397" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2583397" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-46.png" alt="GPT-4 content moderation" width="1024" height="825" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-46.png 1712w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-46.png?resize=150,121 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-46.png?resize=300,242 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-46.png?resize=768,619 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-46.png?resize=680,548 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-46.png?resize=1536,1238 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-46.png?resize=1200,967 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-46.png?resize=50,40 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2583397" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> OpenAI</p></div></p>
<p>OpenAI makes the claim that its process &#8212; which several of its customers are already using &#8212; can reduce the time it takes to roll out new content moderation policies down to hours. And it paints it as superior to the approaches proposed by startups like <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/05/09/anthropic-thinks-constitutional-ai-is-the-best-way-to-train-models/">Anthropic</a>, which OpenAI describes as rigid in its reliance on models&#8217; &#8220;internalized judgments&#8221; as opposed to &#8220;platform-specific . . . iteration.&#8221;</p>
<p>But color me skeptical.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>AI-powered moderation tools are nothing new. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/23/googles-new-project-aims-to-clean-up-comment-sections/">Perspective</a>, maintained by Google’s Counter Abuse Technology Team and the tech giant&#8217;s Jigsaw division, launched in general availability several years ago. Countless startups offer automated moderation services as well, including <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/01/24/spectrum-labs-b/">Spectrum Labs</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/12/08/cinder-builds-a-trust-and-safety-platform/">Cinder</a>, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/04/21/hive-raises-85m-for-ai-based-apis-to-help-moderate-content-identify-objects-and-more/">Hive</a> and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/10/04/reddit-acqui-hires-ml-content-moderation-company-oterlu/">Oterlu</a>, which Reddit recently acquired.</p>
<p>And they don&#8217;t have a perfect track record.</p>
<p>Several years ago, a team at Penn State <a href="https://www.psu.edu/news/information-sciences-and-technology/story/ai-language-models-show-bias-against-people-disabilities/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">found</a> that posts on social media about people with disabilities could be flagged as more negative or toxic by commonly used public sentiment and toxicity detection models. In another <a href="https://news.cs.washington.edu/2019/10/09/allen-school-researchers-find-racial-bias-built-into-hate-speech-detection/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">study</a>, researchers showed that older versions of Perspective often couldn’t recognize hate speech that used &#8220;reclaimed&#8221; slurs like &#8220;queer&#8221; and spelling variations such as missing characters.</p>
<p>Part of the reason for these failures is that annotators &#8212; the people responsible for adding labels to the training datasets that serve as examples for the models &#8212; bring their own biases to the table. For example, frequently, there&#8217;s differences in the annotations between labelers who self-identified as African Americans and members of the LGBTQ+ community versus annotators who don’t identify as either of those two groups.</p>
<p>Has OpenAI solved this problem? I&#8217;d venture to say not quite. The company itself acknowledges this:</p>
<p>&#8220;Judgments by language models are vulnerable to undesired biases that might have been introduced into the model during training,&#8221; the company writes in the post. &#8220;As with any AI application, results and output will need to be carefully monitored, validated and refined by maintaining humans in the loop.&#8221;</p>
<p>Perhaps the predictive strength of GPT-4 can help deliver better moderation performance than the platforms that&#8217;ve come before it. But even the best AI today makes mistakes &#8212; and it&#8217;s crucial we don&#8217;t forget that, especially when it comes to moderation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/openai-proposes-a-new-way-to-use-gpt-4-for-content-moderation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The tech jobs market is as strong as it ever was</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/tech-jobs-market-h1-2023/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/tech-jobs-market-h1-2023/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 18:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC News Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[job market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tech jobs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2583344</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It may feel like the tech jobs market is in the doldrums, but the data suggests that it could be much more robust than you think.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">After the big companies conducted <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/14/tech-industry-layoffs-2023/">mega layoffs</a> at the beginning of this year, it would be natural to think that the tech unemployment rate would skyrocket. If we think about tech jobs as purely IT, engineering and developer kinds of roles, then those jobs are definitely still in demand and less affected than you might imagine.</p>
<p>There’s a big factor working in the favor of tech professionals looking for work: They’re sought after in both the technology industry and across other industries that also require workers with the same technical skills. Those non-technology companies are finally getting a shot at some of the better talent that has been locked in tech industry jobs for the last few years.</p>
<p>Still, when you add tens of thousands of people to the unemployment payroll, it’s bound to have an impact eventually — even if all those jobs weren’t pure tech jobs.</p>
<p>Right after the latest jobs numbers came out earlier this month, the number of <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/08/01/economy/jolts-job-openings-june/index.html?utm_source=twcnnbrk&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_term=link&amp;utm_content=2023-08-01T14%3A23%3A45" target="_blank" rel="noopener">job openings across all sectors fell</a> to its lowest level in two years. What’s more, CompTIA found that tech job posting volume was down, suggesting that companies might have put hiring on hold, at least for the short-term.</p>
<p>This hardly seems surprising, given that the Fed has been raising interest rates for the last 19 months with the specific goal of cooling the economy. In fact, over the last year, rates ballooned from 1.68% in July 2022 to over 5% today. The attempts seemed to have worked if the declining jobs data is any indication.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2583348" style="width: 2630px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2583348" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="breakout wp-image-2583348 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-2023-08-15-at-1.18.06-PM.png" alt="Fed interest rate hikes from July 2022 to July 2023" width="2620" height="878" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-2023-08-15-at-1.18.06-PM.png 2620w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-2023-08-15-at-1.18.06-PM.png?resize=150,50 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-2023-08-15-at-1.18.06-PM.png?resize=300,101 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-2023-08-15-at-1.18.06-PM.png?resize=768,257 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-2023-08-15-at-1.18.06-PM.png?resize=680,228 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-2023-08-15-at-1.18.06-PM.png?resize=1536,515 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-2023-08-15-at-1.18.06-PM.png?resize=2048,686 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-2023-08-15-at-1.18.06-PM.png?resize=1200,402 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-2023-08-15-at-1.18.06-PM.png?resize=50,17 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2620px) 100vw, 2620px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2583348" class="wp-caption-text">Fed interest rate hikes from July 2022 to July 2023 <strong>Image Credits:</strong> FRED</p></div></p>
<p>When we looked at the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/02/16/jobs-layoffs-big-tech/">tech jobs outlook</a> in February, we expected it to be worse than it was, but tech jobs growth remained surprisingly strong. Today, the picture isn’t quite as bright — though not awful — but there is clearly a shifting landscape for tech workers.</p>
<h2>And you may ask yourself, &#8220;How did we get here?&#8221;</h2>
<p>You may recall (or may have stricken it from your memory due to the trauma) that in March 2020, we went into a lockdown. That caused the economy and tech jobs to plunge briefly, but throughout that year and into 2021, companies began recognizing that there was a business opportunity in having so many workers at home.<div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/tech-jobs-market-h1-2023/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Worldcoin ignored initial order to stop iris scans in Kenya, records show</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/worldcoin-in-kenya/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/worldcoin-in-kenya/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Annie Njanja]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 17:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Worldcoin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2583284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Months before Kenya finally banned iris scans by Sam Altman’s crypto startup Worldcoin, the Office of the Data Protection Commissioner (ODPC) had ordered its parent company, Tools for Humanity, to stop collecting personal data. The ODPC had in May this year instructed the crypto startup to stop iris scans and the collection of facial recognition [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Months before<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/02/kenya-suspends-worldcoin-scans-over-security-privacy-and-financial-concerns/?tpcc=tcplustwitter"> Kenya finally banned iris scans by Sam Altman’s crypto startup Worldcoin,</a> the Office of the Data Protection Commissioner (ODPC) had ordered its parent company, Tools for Humanity, to stop collecting personal data.</p>
<p>The ODPC had in May this year instructed the crypto startup to stop iris scans and the collection of facial recognition and other personal data in Kenya, a letter sent to Worldcoin and seen by TechCrunch shows.</p>
<p>Tools for Humanity, the company building Worldcoin, did not stop taking biometric data until early this month when Kenya’s ministry of interior and administration, a more powerful entity, suspended it following its official launch. Worldcoin&#8217;s official launch led to a spike in the number of people queuing up to have their eyeballs scanned in exchange for “free money,” drawing the attention of authorities.</p>
<p>The letter shows that ODPC had instructed Worldcoin to cease collecting data for intruding on individuals’ privacy by gathering biometric data without a well-established and compelling justification. Further, it said Worldcoin had failed to obtain valid consent from people before scanning their irises, saying its agents failed to inform its subjects about the data security and privacy measures it took, and how the data collected would be used or processed.</p>
<p>“Your client is hereby instructed to cease the collection of all facial recognition data and iris scans, from your subscribers. This cessation should be implemented without delay and should include all ongoing and future data processing activities,” said Rose Mosero, in a letter to Tools for Humanity that outlined the concerns. The letter, addressed to Ariana Issaias of Coulson Harney (Bowmans), the law firm representing the crypto startup, also restricted Worldcoin from processing the collected data further and instructed the safe storage of collected information.</p>
<p>Details of ODPC’s attempt to stop the collection of biometric data have emerged in a new petition filed before the High Court by the data protection authority.</p>
<p>The deputy data commissioner of compliance, Oscar Otieno, in an affidavit filed in court in August, said that it started the “assessment” of the respondents (Tools for Humanity and Sense Marketing Limited) in 2022. In May this year, it carried out further inquiry on their processing activities and directed that they cease processing sensitive personal data immediately.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>“The applicant (ODPC) is aware that despite the suspension and directive to cease processing of personal data, the respondents continued to process the said personal data. It took the public directive by the cabinet ministry of interior and coordination to halt the operations of the respondents (Tools for Humanity and Sense Marketing),” said Otieno in the affidavit.</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ZToxWELs43"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/28/world-gdpr-concerns/">Worldcoin&#8217;s official launch triggers swift privacy scrutiny in Europe</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Worldcoin&#8217;s official launch triggers swift privacy scrutiny in Europe&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/28/world-gdpr-concerns/embed/#?secret=KEy4Ru6Zuc#?secret=ZToxWELs43" data-secret="ZToxWELs43" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>The ODPC sought the court&#8217;s help to have Worldcoin compelled to preserve the data it collected from Kenyans, as it finalizes (the multi-agency) investigations around security, privacy, and the legality of using “financial incentive” to obtain biometric data.</p>
<p>Since the filing of the petition, the High Court has <a href="https://www.businessdailyafrica.com/bd/economy/keep-off-kenyans-eyes-court-orders-worldcoin-as-probe-on--4335544" target="_blank" rel="noopener">barred Worldcoin from collecting data from Kenyans</a> and directed it, its agents, its representatives and its employees to preserve all information collected locally from April 19 to August 8.</p>
<p>This has emerged after Worldcoin activities were suspended in Kenya on August 2, by Kithure Kindiki, the country’s cabinet secretary for interior and national administration. Kindiki said the ban will remain in place until the authorities determine “the absence of any risks to the general public whatsoever.”</p>
<p>“Relevant security, financial service and data protection agencies have commenced inquiries and investigations to establish the authenticity and legality of the aforesaid activities, and the safety and protection of the data being harvested, and how the harvesters intend to use the data,” said Kindiki.</p>
<p>Worldcoin claims to be creating a new “human identity (World ID) and financial network” through iris scans done by “Orb,” the company’s spherical scanners to “verify your World ID,” and its own cryptocurrency “WLD.”</p>
<p>Kenya was one of the first countries where Worldcoin launched sign-ups and had been one of the biggest markets for takeup. After the global official launch at the end of July, locals who had received the tokens could sell them for USDT (the stablecoin pegged to the U.S. dollar) on crypto exchanges or to “brokers” in exchange for cash. In Kenya, that promise of “free money” quickly spread across the country, leading to an influx of people at the recruitment (Orb) stations, which drew the attention of top government officials, leading to the suspension of Worldcoin iris scans. The crypto startups said it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/03/worldcoin-plans-to-resume-iris-scans-in-kenya/">hopes to resume activities in Kenya soon</a>.</p>
<p>Alongside the many issues that <a href="https://newsletter.mollywhite.net/p/worldcoin-a-solution-in-search-of" target="_blank" rel="noopener">skeptical peers in the technology industry</a> have been raising about the Worldcoin project and its bigger business ambitions, there are growing concerns about how those efforts to build a biometric database using the promise of free cryptocurrency have exploited economically disadvantaged people. Also, some of these issues have been there in plain sight. An MIT Technology Review <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/04/06/1048981/worldcoin-cryptocurrency-biometrics-web3/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">investigation</a> — published last year — found that it “used deceptive marketing practices, was collecting more personal data than it acknowledged, and failed to obtain meaningful informed consent.”</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="1JBYaeekcR"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/27/are-you-going-to-let-sam-altmans-crypto-project-scan-your-eyeballs-or-not/">Are you going to let Sam Altman’s crypto project scan your eyeballs or not?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Are you going to let Sam Altman’s crypto project scan your eyeballs or not?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/27/are-you-going-to-let-sam-altmans-crypto-project-scan-your-eyeballs-or-not/embed/#?secret=MHunsLDouQ#?secret=1JBYaeekcR" data-secret="1JBYaeekcR" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/worldcoin-in-kenya/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Substack expands further into social networking with a new &#8216;Follow&#8217; button</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/substack-expands-further-into-social-networking-with-a-new-follow-button/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/substack-expands-further-into-social-networking-with-a-new-follow-button/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 17:10:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Substack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2583291</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Substack is adding a new feature to make its platform feel more like a social network, as the company announced on Tuesday that users can now follow writers. The new feature gives users a way to keep up with what a writer is doing without having to subscribe to their newsletter. The company says that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Substack is adding a new feature to make its platform feel more like a social network, as the company <a href="https://on.substack.com/p/follow" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> on Tuesday that users can now follow writers. The new feature gives users a way to keep up with what a writer is doing without having to subscribe to their newsletter.</p>
<p>The company says that since launching its <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/04/05/substacks-new-short-form-notes-feed-looks-a-lot-like-twitter/">Twitter-like Notes</a> feature in April, following has been one of the most requested features from writers and readers. Users can find friends to follow by syncing their phone contacts with Substack.</p>
<p>&#8220;Following helps writers grow their audience via the Substack network, which is already home to millions of the world’s most valuable readers,&#8221; Substack wrote in a blog post. &#8220;We built this feature to help maximize — and not replace — subscriptions, which will always be the most important type of relationship on Substack. A follow offers a lightweight way to start a relationship with a writer or reader, with the option to convert it into a subscription at any time.&#8221;</p>
<p>By following a writer, you can can stay up to date with what they’re reading, liking, publishing, and subscribing to — through the Notes feed and on their profiles.</p>
<p>Substack says that although the &#8220;Subscribe&#8221; button will remain the primary focus when you encounter writers you’re not already following, users will now see a smaller &#8220;Follow&#8221; button on individual notes and profiles. You will also see Follow buttons on lists of suggested accounts.</p>
<p>The platform will encourage users who follow writers to also subscribe to their newsletters. For instance, each time a writer publishes a note, their followers will see it and be prompted to subscribe. In the future, Substack will make “upsells” to subscriptions easier by automatically notifying followers about trending posts and other milestones.</p>
<p>&#8220;In addition to creating this new subscription pathway, the follow feature will help readers more easily share your writing,&#8221; Substack notes. &#8220;For example, if a reader likes or restacks one of your posts, their followers may see that activity in their Notes feed. That means that writers will benefit from these new features even if they’re not active on Notes.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>Although Substack is best known as a newsletter platform, the company has been working on developing traditional social networking features. The addition of a Follow button indicates that the platform is serious about branching out beyond a newsletter platform.</p>
<p>Substack has been looking to take on X (formerly known as Twitter) ever since Elon Musk took the reins of the company last year. The company took a direct shot at X last year, when it <a href="https://on.substack.com/p/bringing-your-twitter-followers-to" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-mrf-link="https://on.substack.com/p/bringing-your-twitter-followers-to">warned in a post</a> that “Twitter is changing, and it’s tough to predict what might be next.” The post had encouraged creators of all sorts to port their Twitter follower base to Substack. Today&#8217;s announcement brings the Substack user experience more in line with X&#8217;s.</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="rh0cdDTGnP"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/04/05/substacks-new-short-form-notes-feed-looks-a-lot-like-twitter/">Substack&#8217;s new short-form &#8216;Notes&#8217; feed looks a lot like Twitter</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Substack&#8217;s new short-form &#8216;Notes&#8217; feed looks a lot like Twitter&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2023/04/05/substacks-new-short-form-notes-feed-looks-a-lot-like-twitter/embed/#?secret=vFQnmC4HLA#?secret=rh0cdDTGnP" data-secret="rh0cdDTGnP" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/substack-expands-further-into-social-networking-with-a-new-follow-button/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>TechCrunch+ Roundup: App Store growth tactics, changing SaaS models, &#8216;AI-induced frenzy&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/app-store-growth-tactics-changing-saas-models-ai-induced-frenzy/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/app-store-growth-tactics-changing-saas-models-ai-induced-frenzy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Walter Thompson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 17:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CISO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC roundup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Generative AI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2583281</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Given the hype around generative AI, it's easy to forget that IBM Watson competed on Jeopardy in 2011 — and won a $1M first-place prize. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Given the hype around generative AI, it&#8217;s easy to forget that IBM Watson competed on &#8220;Jeopardy&#8221; in 2011 — and won a $1 million first-place prize.</p>
<p>For years, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/13/is-ai-platform-or-market/">enterprise software companies have baked this tech into their offerings</a>, such as Salesforce&#8217;s Einstein and Microsoft Cortana.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><i>Full TechCrunch+ articles are only available to members<br />
<a href="https://techcrunch.com/subscribe/">Use discount code <strong>TCPLUSROUNDUP</strong></a> to save 20% off a one- or two-year subscription</i></p>
<hr />
<p>&#8220;As we find ourselves in the midst of this AI-induced frenzy, it could be useful to take a step back and see just what we are dealing with here,&#8221; writes Ron Miller.</p>
<p>&#8220;Is there actually an AI market in the pure sense, or is it enabling technology that will soon be built into everything, making how we view it less clear?&#8221;</p>
<p>Thanks for reading TC+ this week,</p>
<p>Walter Thompson<br />
Editorial Manager, TechCrunch+</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="0xArqbRaZy"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/13/is-ai-platform-or-market/">Sure AI is hot, but is it an actual market or a platform piece?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Sure AI is hot, but is it an actual market or a platform piece?&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/13/is-ai-platform-or-market/embed/#?secret=6Dbs2qIQDx#?secret=0xArqbRaZy" data-secret="0xArqbRaZy" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Deal Dive: This AI startup is racking up government customers</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2582410" style="width: 2069px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2582410" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2582410 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1398401418.jpg" alt="tax evasion, IVIX, startup, government" width="2059" height="1456" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1398401418.jpg 2059w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1398401418.jpg?resize=150,106 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1398401418.jpg?resize=300,212 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1398401418.jpg?resize=768,543 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1398401418.jpg?resize=680,481 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1398401418.jpg?resize=1536,1086 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1398401418.jpg?resize=2048,1448 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1398401418.jpg?resize=1200,849 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1398401418.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2059px) 100vw, 2059px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2582410" class="wp-caption-text">IVIX has landed multiple government contracts for its tech that helps agencies spot financial crimes. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>For her latest Deal Dive column, Rebecca Szkutak profiled Tel Aviv–based IVIX, which &#8220;uses AI, machine learning and public databases&#8221; to track tax cheats and other bad actors.</p>
<p>The company launched in 2020, and co-founders Matan Fattal and Doron Passov recently closed a $12.5 million Series A and already count multiple agencies as customers.</p>
<p>&#8220;I was shocked by the magnitude of the problem and the technical gap that they had,&#8221; said Fattal.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="WXcNNsYHyC"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/12/ivix-ai-financial-crimes/">Deal Dive: This AI startup is racking up government customers</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Deal Dive: This AI startup is racking up government customers&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/12/ivix-ai-financial-crimes/embed/#?secret=tqIhklDqnu#?secret=WXcNNsYHyC" data-secret="WXcNNsYHyC" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>How we scaled our App Store performance by approximately 200% in 1 year</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2581646" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2581646" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2581646" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1307645589.jpg" alt="App launch. Startup vector concept, flat cartoon rocket or rocketship launch, mobile phone or smartphone, idea of successful business project start up, boost technology, innovation." width="1024" height="683" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1307645589.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1307645589.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1307645589.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1307645589.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1307645589.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1307645589.jpg?resize=1200,800 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-1307645589.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2581646" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?photographer=PaperFox" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PaperFox <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>Building, testing and deploying apps that meet Apple&#8217;s approval is just the first part of the journey: To drive downloads and conversions, dev teams need someone who understands App Store Optimization (ASO) and Apple Search Ads (ASA).</p>
<p>ASO/ASA specialist Olga Bakirova shares a detailed implementation guide with TC+ that lays out the tactics and strategy she&#8217;s using to promote her company&#8217;s edtech app.</p>
<p>After conducting a series of A/B tests and testing keyword campaigns and custom product images, &#8220;the overall number of downloads increased by 210%, and purchases surged by 157%,&#8221; she writes.</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jnXqD4B78K"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/11/how-we-scaled-our-app-store-performance-by-approximately-200-in-1-year/">How we scaled our App Store performance by approximately 200% in 1 year</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How we scaled our App Store performance by approximately 200% in 1 year&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/11/how-we-scaled-our-app-store-performance-by-approximately-200-in-1-year/embed/#?secret=Nsp1yMKpwY#?secret=jnXqD4B78K" data-secret="jnXqD4B78K" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Get the TechCrunch+ Roundup newsletter in your inbox!</h2>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2554001" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/sign-up-for-newsletters.png" alt="sign up for the TechCrunch+ roundup newsletter" width="1024" height="230" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/sign-up-for-newsletters.png 1726w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/sign-up-for-newsletters.png?resize=150,34 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/sign-up-for-newsletters.png?resize=300,67 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/sign-up-for-newsletters.png?resize=768,173 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/sign-up-for-newsletters.png?resize=680,153 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/sign-up-for-newsletters.png?resize=1536,345 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/sign-up-for-newsletters.png?resize=1200,270 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/sign-up-for-newsletters.png?resize=50,11 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />To receive the TechCrunch+ Roundup as an email each Tuesday and Friday, scroll down to find the “sign up for newsletters” section on this page, select “TechCrunch+ Roundup,” enter your email, and click “subscribe.”</p>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><strong><a href="https://link.techcrunch.com/join/134/signup-all-newsletters">Click here to subscribe</a></strong></h3>
<h2>A core plank of the SaaS economic model is under extreme pressure</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_1882594" style="width: 5626px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1882594" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-1882594 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-117149428.jpg" alt="Stressed business man sitting on floor with papers falling around him" width="5616" height="3952" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-117149428.jpg 5616w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-117149428.jpg?resize=150,106 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-117149428.jpg?resize=300,211 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-117149428.jpg?resize=768,540 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-117149428.jpg?resize=680,479 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-117149428.jpg?resize=1536,1081 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-117149428.jpg?resize=2048,1441 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-117149428.jpg?resize=1200,844 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/GettyImages-117149428.jpg?resize=50,35 50w" sizes="(max-width: 5616px) 100vw, 5616px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1882594" class="wp-caption-text">Stressed business man sitting on floor with papers falling around him. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> GlobalStock / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>It used to be a given that SaaS startups with a firm handle on growth, churn and product-market fit would find themselves in net revenue retention (NRR) territory, writes Alex Wilhelm.</p>
<p>However, recent earnings reports show &#8220;a decline in SaaS net retention from Q1 2022 to Q1 2023&#8221; for public companies like Snowflake, Cloudflare and Amplitude.</p>
<p>&#8220;Amazon and Google and Microsoft can take IaaS and PaaS deceleration on the chin,&#8221; notes Alex, but &#8220;for tech shops with more targeted incomes, the issue can be steeper.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="bBm2PslgHW"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/12/saas-economic-model-pressure/">A core plank of the SaaS economic model is under extreme pressure</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;A core plank of the SaaS economic model is under extreme pressure&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/12/saas-economic-model-pressure/embed/#?secret=EzuFhS0LM9#?secret=bBm2PslgHW" data-secret="bBm2PslgHW" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>Enterprise spending on cybersecurity has changed, and vendors must adapt</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2582456" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2582456" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2582456" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-96260455.jpg" alt="Pinching a Penny in C Clamp" width="1024" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-96260455.jpg 1500w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-96260455.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-96260455.jpg?resize=300,199 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-96260455.jpg?resize=768,510 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-96260455.jpg?resize=680,452 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-96260455.jpg?resize=1200,797 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/GettyImages-96260455.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2582456" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> <a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/search/photographer?photographer=herreid14" target="_blank" rel="noopener">herreid14 <span class="screen-reader-text">(opens in a new window)</span></a> / Getty Images</p></div></p>
<p>What&#8217;s happened to cybersecurity spending over the last year?</p>
<p>A report by YL Ventures that pulled data from &#8220;Fortune 1000 CISOs and cybersecurity decision-makers&#8221; showed that compliance/risk management and cloud security were top priorities.</p>
<p>In an environment where so many companies have frozen or dialed back on spending, only &#8220;half of CISOs can still accommodate new solutions,&#8221; writes YL&#8217;s Sara Behar.</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="jar7LMMUL7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/14/enterprise-spending-on-cybersecurity-has-changed-and-vendors-must-adapt/">Enterprise spending on cybersecurity has changed, and vendors must adapt</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Enterprise spending on cybersecurity has changed, and vendors must adapt&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/14/enterprise-spending-on-cybersecurity-has-changed-and-vendors-must-adapt/embed/#?secret=Zvy2s7xDrZ#?secret=jar7LMMUL7" data-secret="jar7LMMUL7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<h2>The civil rights movement comes to venture capital</h2>
<p><div id="attachment_2582390" style="width: 6440px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2582390" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2582390 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/So-whats-Next.jpg" alt="The founders of Fearless Fund and their legal counsel stand for photos at a press conference in New York City." width="6430" height="4287" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/So-whats-Next.jpg 6430w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/So-whats-Next.jpg?resize=150,100 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/So-whats-Next.jpg?resize=300,200 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/So-whats-Next.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/So-whats-Next.jpg?resize=680,453 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/So-whats-Next.jpg?resize=1536,1024 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/So-whats-Next.jpg?resize=2048,1365 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/So-whats-Next.jpg?resize=1200,800 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/So-whats-Next.jpg?resize=50,33 50w" sizes="(max-width: 6430px) 100vw, 6430px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2582390" class="wp-caption-text">The founders of Fearless Fund and their legal counsel stand for photos at a press conference in New York City. <strong>Image Credits:</strong> Fearless Fund</p></div></p>
<p>A nonprofit founded by anti-affirmative action activist Edward Blum recently sued Atlanta-based Fearless Fund. Because the group awards $20,000 to Black women entrepreneurs, American Alliance for Equal Rights claims it violates federal civil rights legislation.</p>
<p>In light of the fact that Black women receive less than 0.5% of venture capital allocated each year, Dominic-Madori Davis looked at how funding &#8220;has always been a civil rights issue, just one river feeding the ocean of persistent economic segregation.&#8221;</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cJFswWR7E7"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/11/fearless-fund-lawsuit-civil-rights/">The civil rights movement comes to venture capital</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The civil rights movement comes to venture capital&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/11/fearless-fund-lawsuit-civil-rights/embed/#?secret=fFHfStT1bB#?secret=cJFswWR7E7" data-secret="cJFswWR7E7" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/app-store-growth-tactics-changing-saas-models-ai-induced-frenzy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The pre-seed market is recovering, but investors increasingly have the upper hand</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/the-investors-have-the-high-ground-luke/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/the-investors-have-the-high-ground-luke/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 17:04:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2023 investing trends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC Newsletter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EC venture capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pre-seed funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pre-seed startup fundraising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2583142</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While funding to pre-seed startups has picked up pace, most of the deals being closed are more in favor of investors than the founders.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">While it&#8217;s often held that the early-stage investing market has <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/14/seed-market-deal-counts-down">generally fared better</a> in this <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/13/welcome-to-the-new-venture-normal/">funding slowdown of the last 18 months or so</a>, things haven&#8217;t actually been very good for pre-seed startups trying to raise money.</p>
<p>Thankfully, it appears the pre-seed market is starting to recover, per new <a href="https://carta.com/blog/state-of-pre-seed-fundraising-q2-2023/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">data from Carta</a>, which provides cap table management software for startups.</p>
<hr />
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>More: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/26/5-founders-discuss-why-safes-are-better-for-early-stage-and-bridge-rounds/">5 founders discuss why SAFEs are better for early-stage and bridge rounds</a></strong></p>
<hr />
<p>The news is not all good, though — for founders, at least. The data indicates investor-friendly terms are becoming more common, which is not entirely unexpected. As the venture market has cooled and investors became pickier, founders have found it more difficult to bargain for clean term sheets or aggressive valuations.</p>
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/tag/the-exchange/"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-2220366 size-medium" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?w=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=768,768 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=680,680 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/exchange-banner-sq-blu-plus.jpg?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>So, what can founders expect if they&#8217;re looking to raise their first round of capital these days? Let&#8217;s find out.</p>
<p><em>Shameless plug: <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/04/25/builders-stage-agenda-disrupt-2023/">The Builders Stage at Disrupt this year</a> is going to have a lot of related material on fundraising and scaling startups. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2023/">Come hang out</a>!</em></p>
<h2>The good, the bad, the pre-seed</h2>
<p>Altogether, pre-seed startups that use Carta raised $972 million in the second quarter, 17% more than they did in the first quarter. That kind of recovery feels material, but the difference is stark when you consider the fact that funding to pre-seed startups remained above the $1.40 billion mark throughout the first half of 2022.</p>
<p>(Note that Carta&#8217;s customers are mostly based in the United States, so this data primarily reflects trends in the U.S.)</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PCF9UutU57"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/14/venture-capital-is-doing-better/">8 reasons why the venture capital market isn&#8217;t as miserable as you think</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;8 reasons why the venture capital market isn&#8217;t as miserable as you think&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/14/venture-capital-is-doing-better/embed/#?secret=QtmdEN8aOz#?secret=PCF9UutU57" data-secret="PCF9UutU57" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<p>Still, it seems fewer deals were closed in that period, marking the fourth straight quarter of declines in the number of pre-seed deals: Carta recorded 1,608 pre-seed rounds in the second quarter, down from 1,820 in the first quarter.</p>
<p>More dollars with fewer rounds appears to be the story of the pre-seed market in these times. Now, let&#8217;s get into the weeds.</p>
<p><div class="extra-crunch-offer-container"></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/the-investors-have-the-high-ground-luke/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vlad Tenev shares Robinhood’s next chapter at TechCrunch Disrupt 2023</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/vlad-tenev-shares-robinhoods-next-chapter-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2023/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/vlad-tenev-shares-robinhoods-next-chapter-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2023/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lauren Simonds]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 16:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fintech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC Disrupt 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TechCrunch Disrupt 2023]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2582558</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Robinhood launched a decade ago as a stock trading and investing app. During that time, it’s become a retail investment behemoth — but not without its share of controversy, including the GameStop trade freeze of 2021 and two rounds of layoffs last year. Add to that a declining user base and it begs the question, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Robinhood launched a decade ago as a stock trading and investing app. During that time, it’s become a retail investment behemoth — but not without its share of controversy, including the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/06/27/robinhood-report-meme-stock-gamestop/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GameStop trade freeze</a> of 2021 and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/08/02/robinhood-23-layoff-vlad-tenev-responsibility-hiring/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">two rounds of layoffs</a> last year. Add to that a declining user base and it begs the question, what’s next for Robinhood?</p>
<p>We’re excited to announce that we’ll all learn the answer to that question when Vlad Tenev, the company’s co-founder and CEO, joins us on the Fintech Stage for a session called &#8220;What’s Robinhood’s Next Chapter?” on September 19 during TechCrunch Disrupt 2023.</p>
<p>The company has been busy expanding its product portfolio. Last year, it <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/12/06/fintech-robinhood-banks-on-retirement/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">unveiled Robinhood Retirement</a>, an IRA designed for people — think gig workers and contractors — who work outside the typical 9–5 grind. They generally find it hard to save for retirement without full-time job benefits like employer-sponsored 401K plans.</p>
<p>This past June, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/06/22/robinhood-acquires-credit-card-startup-x1-for-95m/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the company acquired X1</a>, a no-fee credit card startup, for $95 million. The slowdown in crypto trading and a decline in Robinhood’s core trading business may be the impetus for diversifying its business.</p>
<p>Fintech’s been a roller-coaster ride for just about everyone since <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/01/02/fintech-predictions-and-opportunities-for-2023/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the highs of 2021</a> — as Tenev can readily attest. We’re looking forward to learning what to expect in the popular trading app’s next chapter.</p>
<h2>Vlad Tenev: Robinhood Markets’ co-founder and CEO</h2>
<p>Vlad Tenev co-founded Robinhood with Baiju Bhatt in 2013 with a mission to democratize finance. They served as co-CEOs and co-presidents until 2020, when Tenev took on those roles. He is also chair of the company’s board of directors.</p>
<p>Prior to Robinhood, Tenev started two finance companies in New York City. Tenev holds a degree in mathematics from Stanford University and an MS in mathematics from UCLA.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2023/?utm_source=tc&amp;utm_medium=post&amp;utm_campaign=disrupt2023&amp;utm_content=post_vlad&amp;promo=post_vlad&amp;display=" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TechCrunch Disrupt 2023</a> takes place on September 19–21 in San Francisco. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/events/tc-disrupt-2023/tickets/?utm_source=tc&amp;utm_medium=post&amp;utm_campaign=disrupt2023&amp;utm_content=post_vlad&amp;promo=post_vlad" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Buy your pass today</a> and save. Prices go up at the door.</p>
<p><i>Is your company interested in sponsoring or exhibiting at TechCrunch Disrupt 2023? Contact our sponsorship sales team by </i><a href="http://info.techcrunch.com/SponsorshipsInterest.html?_ga=2.147735806.874617471.1572269011-985484541.1566312242" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i>filling out this form</i></a><i>.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/vlad-tenev-shares-robinhoods-next-chapter-at-techcrunch-disrupt-2023/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Setapp announces plans to launch an alt app store for EU users</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/setapp-announces-plans-to-launch-an-alt-app-store-for-eu-users/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/setapp-announces-plans-to-launch-an-alt-app-store-for-eu-users/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 16:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app stores]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DMA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eu]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2583246</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[App subscription service Setapp is preparing to launch as an alternative app store, as soon as new EU regulations come into effect next year. The company is betting on the EU&#8217;s Digital Markets Act&#8217;s (DMA) rules that should allow users to install third-party apps on iOS without having to go through Apple&#8217;s App Store. However, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">App subscription service <a href="https://setapp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Setapp</a> is preparing to launch as an alternative app store, as soon as <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/07/05/dma-dsa-eu-parliament-vote/">new EU regulations</a> come into effect next year. The company is betting on the EU&#8217;s Digital Markets Act&#8217;s (DMA) rules that should allow users to <a href="https://news.yahoo.com/eu-apple-to-allow-outside-app-stores-111215682.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAIjoCruyN4Db4Ob2XQPxVTgq9HncYG13oMpD8HPspDSEYMUKe7cyWLMy4ZGJ_HKoUSpBOGJ0DGW-4vmMO3e0jObfzlxlg31huDhflTC_XCyEcHbK6UIURluegWo6rjWeCrCUcRNrPpwa5AtDE7uQWV1UlkZiNiVvNkajY_vbX8hs" target="_blank" rel="noopener">install third-party apps</a> on iOS without having to go through Apple&#8217;s App Store.</p>
<p>However, how Apple chooses to interpret the new law remains unclear.</p>
<p>A December 2022 report from <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-12-13/will-apple-allow-users-to-install-third-party-app-stores-sideload-in-europe?sref=gni836kR">Bloomberg</a> indicated Apple was preparing to allow alternative app stores on iPhones and iPads to come into compliance with the DMA, despite its ongoing concerns over the security issues involved with &#8220;sideloading&#8221; apps, which can impact consumers&#8217; safety and privacy. But, the report noted, the tech giant was still discussing other ideas about how this new system would work &#8212; perhaps even requiring these apps to be verified by Apple for a fee.</p>
<p>In the meantime, though, Setapp is moving forward with the assumption that Apple devices will ultimately have to support third-party app stores and is working on plans to launch its own.</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr"><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f4e3.png" alt="📣" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Exciting news for iPhone users in Europe! <a href="https://twitter.com/Setapp?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Setapp</a>, the ultimate app subscription service for macOS and iOS, is planning to launch as an alternative app store! </p>
<p>Join the waitlist and be the first to explore: <a href="https://t.co/pbpcM5JzvP">https://t.co/pbpcM5JzvP</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Apple?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Apple</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AppStore?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#AppStore</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DMA?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DMA</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DigitalMarketsAct?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DigitalMarketsAct</a> <a href="https://t.co/ECgthzXzt1">pic.twitter.com/ECgthzXzt1</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Setapp (@Setapp) <a href="https://twitter.com/Setapp/status/1691434679973318656?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 15, 2023</a></p></blockquote><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>
<p>The company today offers an <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/01/24/mac-app-subscription-service-setapp-has-15000-subscribers-a-year-after-its-launch/?ncid=rss">app subscription service</a> where users pay a fee of $9.99 per month in order to gain access to over 240 apps for their Mac, including utilities, productivity software, customization tools, lifestyle applications, and more. <a href="https://setapp.com/pricing?ci=11843244237&amp;adgroupid=141956831037&amp;adpos=&amp;ck=setapp%20price&amp;targetid=kwd-467858210577&amp;match=e&amp;gnetwork=g&amp;creative=625361443809&amp;placement=&amp;placecat=&amp;accname=setapp&amp;extensionid=45221268670&amp;gad=1&amp;gclid=CjwKCAjwxOymBhAFEiwAnodBLCn7m5EA3eT-_t7CTb6Jzk65cbE_PAtayh_a_2C8RuE-oCk4IImoRxoCElIQAvD_BwE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Other plans include</a> those that also offer apps for iOS devices ($12.49/mo), for power users with more devices ($14.99/mo), in addition to family plans and Setapp for teams.</p>
<p>For the new stand-alone app store, Setapp claims to have over 30 partners on board prepared to offer their apps, including Ulysses, Taskheat, NotePlan, PDFSearch, and Soulver, according to its <a href="https://www.craft.me/s/jGw0CWXB8j6p6P" target="_blank" rel="noopener">press release</a>. It&#8217;s also calling for more developers to submit their own.</p>
<p>The company aims to entice developers with better revenue shares than Apple provides. The company offers a 70/30 split with developers when customers use their app during the month, but it additionally shares 20% with developers who bring in new customers &#8212; that means developers have the potential to earn up to 90% from Setapp&#8217;s user fees every month.</p>
<p>“With 60% of developers interested in distributing their iOS apps through third-party app stores, we are excited to extend our support to iOS-only developers and provide them with a platform to grow users and add revenue streams,” said Oleksandr Kosovan, founder and CEO of Setapp, in a statement.</p>
<p>The company is <a href="https://setapp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">offering a waitlist</a> for customers who want to hear about the new store when it launches.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/setapp-announces-plans-to-launch-an-alt-app-store-for-eu-users/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Linear TV viewing sinks below 50% as streaming soars to new heights</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/linear-tv-viewing-sinks-below-50-nielsen-july-2023-report/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/linear-tv-viewing-sinks-below-50-nielsen-july-2023-report/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lauren Forristal]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 16:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Media & Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nielsen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[streaming service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2583256</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a first for linear TV viewing, cable and broadcast usage fell below 50% in terms of total share among U.S. viewers, according to Nielsen’s July 2023 report. Cable viewing dropped below 30% for the first time at 29.6%, down 12.5% year-over-year. Broadcast usage decreased to 20%, down 5.4% YoY. Streaming services, on the other [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">In a first for linear TV viewing, cable and broadcast usage fell below 50% in terms of total share among U.S. viewers, according to Nielsen’s <a href="https://www.nielsen.com/insights/2023/streaming-grabs-a-record-38-7-of-total-tv-usage-in-july-with-acquired-titles-outpacing-new-originals/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">July 2023 report</a>. Cable viewing dropped below 30% for the first time at 29.6%, down 12.5% year-over-year. Broadcast usage decreased to 20%, down 5.4% YoY.</p>
<p>Streaming services, on the other hand, accounted for 38.7% of total U.S. TV usage &#8212; a new record high for the category. Streaming usage has sky-rocketed 25.3% in the past year.</p>
<p>Moreover, there are three streaming platforms in particular that accomplished notable shares of TV usage in July. YouTube and Netflix were top contributors to the rise in streaming viewership, with shares climbing to 9.2% and 8.5%, respectively. Also, Prime Video recorded a personal best in terms of share; viewing was 3.4%, up 5% compared to June.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2583258" style="width: 3850px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Nielsen_the-gauge-JULY-2023-4k@2x.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2583258" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2583258 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Nielsen_the-gauge-JULY-2023-4k@2x.png" alt="" width="3840" height="2160" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Nielsen_the-gauge-JULY-2023-4k@2x.png 3840w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Nielsen_the-gauge-JULY-2023-4k@2x.png?resize=150,84 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Nielsen_the-gauge-JULY-2023-4k@2x.png?resize=300,169 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Nielsen_the-gauge-JULY-2023-4k@2x.png?resize=768,432 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Nielsen_the-gauge-JULY-2023-4k@2x.png?resize=680,383 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Nielsen_the-gauge-JULY-2023-4k@2x.png?resize=1536,864 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Nielsen_the-gauge-JULY-2023-4k@2x.png?resize=2048,1152 2048w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Nielsen_the-gauge-JULY-2023-4k@2x.png?resize=1200,675 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Nielsen_the-gauge-JULY-2023-4k@2x.png?resize=50,28 50w" sizes="(max-width: 3840px) 100vw, 3840px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2583258" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Nielsen</p></div></p>
<p>Streaming has occupied the TV usage throne for years now. For instance, streaming viewership exceeded cable usage for the first time last year, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/08/18/streaming-viewership-surpassed-cable-tv-for-the-first-time-says-nielsen/">according to Nielsen</a>, representing a 34.8% share of total TV viewing in the U.S. However, this doesn’t make the new milestone for broadcast and cable any less bleak. To further put things into perspective, linear TV’s share of viewing represented 63.6% of total TV usage in June 2021, per Nielsen. Now it represents only 49.6%.</p>
<p>Previously, cord-cutters pointed to streaming services’ low prices as the reason for dropping their cable TV packages. However, this may no longer be the case.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/02e7e67d-8367-427e-9aa7-e66c7f7fa8a1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Financial Times</a> recently published data that showed the top U.S. platforms will cost $87 per month in total this fall. The average cable subscription is cheaper at $83 per month, according to the FT.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>In order to limit billion-dollar streaming losses, many companies have implemented subscription price hikes.</p>
<p>Last week, Disney <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/10/disney-announces-another-price-hike-says-ad-supported-tier-is-coming-to-more-countries/">announced</a> yet another round of price increases for Disney+, Hulu and ESPN+. Additionally, Netflix <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/19/netflix-removes-its-basic-tier-in-the-us-and-the-uk/">removed its basic ad-free plan</a> in the U.S., the U.K. and <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/06/26/netflix-quietly-axes-its-basic-plan-in-canada/">Canada</a> in an effort to drive customers to its $15.49/month standard tier.</p>
<p>Disney’s price hike comes as Disney+ continues to <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/09/disney-hotstar-lost-12-5-million-subscribers-in-a-quarter-amid-cricket-shortfall/">lose subscribers</a> for the <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/05/10/disney-q2-2023-results/">third consecutive quarter</a>. The company also <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/10/after-netflix-disney-is-cracking-down-on-password-sharing/">said</a> that it would follow in <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/19/netflix-account-password-sharing-crackdown/">Netflix’s footsteps</a> regarding password-sharing rules.</p>
<p>Subsequently, tons of users are turning to free ad-supported streaming TV (FAST) services to get their entertainment fix. <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/09/free-ad-supported-tv-streaming-services-are-booming-1-in-3-u-s-viewers-tune-in/">Samba TV</a> recently reported that one in three U.S. users subscribes to FAST services such as Freevee, Pluto TV, Tubi, the Roku Channel and Crackle.</p>
<p>As FAST viewing continues to be a growing trend, it’s likely that major subscription video streaming services will have a difficult time convincing customers that they’re worth the hefty price tag.</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="kxKnN7xDnj"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/09/free-ad-supported-tv-streaming-services-are-booming-1-in-3-u-s-viewers-tune-in/">Free ad-supported TV streaming services are booming, 1 in 3 U.S. viewers tune in</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Free ad-supported TV streaming services are booming, 1 in 3 U.S. viewers tune in&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/09/free-ad-supported-tv-streaming-services-are-booming-1-in-3-u-s-viewers-tune-in/embed/#?secret=esWRjwcNSf#?secret=kxKnN7xDnj" data-secret="kxKnN7xDnj" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="oL9iGvSk6z"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/08/18/streaming-viewership-surpassed-cable-tv-for-the-first-time-says-nielsen/">Streaming viewership surpassed cable TV for the first time, says Nielsen</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Streaming viewership surpassed cable TV for the first time, says Nielsen&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2022/08/18/streaming-viewership-surpassed-cable-tv-for-the-first-time-says-nielsen/embed/#?secret=FpUo4gqtal#?secret=oL9iGvSk6z" data-secret="oL9iGvSk6z" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/linear-tv-viewing-sinks-below-50-nielsen-july-2023-report/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google&#8217;s AI search experience adds AI-powered summaries, definitions and coding improvements</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/googles-ai-search-experience-adds-ai-powered-summaries-definitions-and-coding-improvements/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/googles-ai-search-experience-adds-ai-powered-summaries-definitions-and-coding-improvements/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Perez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 16:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artifical intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2583168</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google today is rolling out a few new updates to its nearly three-month-old Search Generative Experience (SGE), the company&#8217;s AI-powered conversational mode in Search, with a goal of helping users better learn and make sense of the information they discover on the web. The features include tools to see definitions of unfamiliar terms, those that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">Google today is rolling out a few new updates to its nearly three-month-old <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/05/10/google-is-experimenting-with-a-new-ai-powered-conversational-mode-in-search/">Search Generative Experience (SGE)</a>, the company&#8217;s AI-powered conversational mode in Search, with a goal of helping users better learn and make sense of the information they discover on the web. The features include tools to see definitions of unfamiliar terms, those that help to improve your understanding and coding information across languages, and an interesting feature that lets you tap into the AI power of SGE while you&#8217;re browsing.</p>
<p>The company <a href="https://blog.google/products/search/google-search-generative-ai-learning-features/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">explains</a> that these improvements aim to help people better understand complicated concepts or complex topics, boost their coding skills and more.</p>
<p>One of the new features will let you hover over certain words to preview their definitions and see related images or diagrams related to the topic, which you can then tap on to learn more. This feature will become available across Google&#8217;s AI-generated responses to topics or questions related to certain subjects, like STEM, economics, history and others, where you may encounter terms you don&#8217;t understand or concepts you want to dive deeper into for a better understanding.</p>
<p>Bing Chat also <a href="https://blogs.bing.com/search/may_2023/Continuing-to-deliver-new-AI-innovation-in-Bing-and-Edge-this-week">offers a feature similar</a> to this that lets you highlight the text in question on a page and then select Bing from the options menu to engage in a conversation where you can learn more about the topic.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2583179" style="width: 1450px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2583179" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2583179 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Inline-definitions.gif" alt="" width="1440" height="1068" /><p id="caption-attachment-2583179" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>Another new feature will help those using SGE for programming assistance. The new capabilities will make it easier to understand and debug the generated code, says Google.</p>
<p>Currently, SGE provides AI-generated overviews that help with tasks related to programming languages and tools, allowing users to find answers to their how-to questions or see generated code snippets. The new update will now color-code segments of code with syntax highlights, making it easier to identify different elements like keywords, comments and strings.</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p>SGE while browsing may be the most interesting new addition, but for now it&#8217;s only an early experiment in Search Labs, available on the Google app for Android and iOS and later, Chrome on the desktop.</p>
<p>The feature is designed to help web users engage with long-form content from publishers and creators, to make it easier to find what they&#8217;re looking for.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2583181" style="width: 2010px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2583181" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2583181 size-full" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/SGE-while-browsing-desktop.png" alt="" width="2000" height="1200" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/SGE-while-browsing-desktop.png 2000w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/SGE-while-browsing-desktop.png?resize=150,90 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/SGE-while-browsing-desktop.png?resize=300,180 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/SGE-while-browsing-desktop.png?resize=768,461 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/SGE-while-browsing-desktop.png?resize=680,408 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/SGE-while-browsing-desktop.png?resize=1536,922 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/SGE-while-browsing-desktop.png?resize=1200,720 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/SGE-while-browsing-desktop.png?resize=50,30 50w" sizes="(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2583181" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>For instance, on some web pages, you can tap to see an AI-generated list of the key points an article covers with links that take you directly to the part you were looking for.</p>
<p>The page will also include an &#8220;Explore on page&#8221; option where you can see the questions an article answers and then jump to the relevant section.</p>
<p>The feature is reminiscent of the existing <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2020/06/04/google-highlighting-results-on-webpages/">content highlighting search feature</a> that will jump you to relevant text when you search for specific terms and a matching result is found. However, this time it&#8217;s powered by AI.</p>
<p>Rival <a href="https://blogs.bing.com/search/may_2023/Continuing-to-deliver-new-AI-innovation-in-Bing-and-Edge-this-week" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bing Chat also already offers a similar feature</a> that lets you tap the Bing Chat icon while reading an article or document online and ask Chat to summarize the content for you &#8212; so this, again, is a little bit of catch-up on Google&#8217;s part.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2583180" style="width: 332px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2583180" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2583180" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/SGE-while-browsing-Key-points-mobile.png?w=322" alt="" width="322" height="680" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/SGE-while-browsing-Key-points-mobile.png 568w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/SGE-while-browsing-Key-points-mobile.png?resize=71,150 71w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/SGE-while-browsing-Key-points-mobile.png?resize=142,300 142w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/SGE-while-browsing-Key-points-mobile.png?resize=322,680 322w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/SGE-while-browsing-Key-points-mobile.png?resize=24,50 24w" sizes="(max-width: 322px) 100vw, 322px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2583180" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>Google notes this feature will not provide AI summaries for paywalled articles, and publishers can choose to block the feature by designating their content as paywalled in the <a href="https://developers.google.com/search/docs/appearance/structured-data/paywalled-content" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Help Center</a>.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2583177" style="width: 331px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2583177" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="vertical size-large wp-image-2583177" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/SGE-while-browsing-mobile.gif?w=321" alt="" width="321" height="680" /><p id="caption-attachment-2583177" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> Google</p></div></p>
<p>Google and Bing are not the only ones thinking about how AI can be used to summarize text. News reading app Artifact, from Instagram&#8217;s founders, <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/04/25/news-app-artifact-can-now-summarize-stories-using-ai-including-in-fun-styles/">also began offering an AI summary feature</a> as of its April 2023 update.</p>
<p>SGE while browsing is available as a stand-alone experiment in Search Labs, and will automatically roll out to those who have already opted into SGE.</p>
<p>The features follow other new additions to SGE, including a feature launched earlier this month that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/02/googles-generative-search-feature-now-shows-related-videos-and-images/">shows videos and images</a> related to users&#8217; search queries.</p>
<p>Search Labs is available through the Google app on Android and iOS and Chrome on the desktop.</p>
<div class="embed breakout embed-oembed embed--techcrunch">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="BXfAobSYMf"><p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/02/googles-generative-search-feature-now-shows-related-videos-and-images/">Google&#8217;s generative search feature now shows related videos and images</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Google&#8217;s generative search feature now shows related videos and images&#8221; &#8212; TechCrunch" src="https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/02/googles-generative-search-feature-now-shows-related-videos-and-images/embed/#?secret=nSuc8Rr6ZC#?secret=BXfAobSYMf" data-secret="BXfAobSYMf" width="800" height="450" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/googles-ai-search-experience-adds-ai-powered-summaries-definitions-and-coding-improvements/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>YouTube Music is adding a TikTok-style &#8216;Samples&#8217; short-form video feed</title>
		<link>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/youtube-music-adding-tiktok-style-samples-short-form-video-feed/</link>
					<comments>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/youtube-music-adding-tiktok-style-samples-short-form-video-feed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aisha Malik]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 16:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media & Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short-form video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube Music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/?p=2582363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[YouTube Music is launching a new TikTok-style short-form personalized video feed called &#8220;Samples,&#8221; the company announced on Monday. Each clip in the feed offers a glimpse into the artist, music video and feel of a song recommended to you. As with TikTok and other copycat short-form video feeds, users can swipe vertically in the new [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="speakable-summary">YouTube Music is launching a new TikTok-style short-form personalized video feed called &#8220;Samples,&#8221; the company announced on Monday. Each clip in the feed offers a glimpse into the artist, music video and feel of a song recommended to you. As with TikTok and other copycat short-form video feeds, users can swipe vertically in the new Samples feed to discover songs and music videos.</p>
<p>Brandon Bilinski, one of YouTube&#8217;s directors of product management, told TechCrunch in an interview that the company is seeing that users are discovering more and more music through short-form video.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of the biggest insights we&#8217;ve seen over the past couple of years is that all users but especially younger users are discovering more and more music through short-form video,&#8221; Bilinski said. &#8220;Friends and family is always number one. If you ask people how they discover music, they always say friends and family, but just recently short-form video climbed into a close number two. We sort of took that insight and we decided to make a discovery focused, short-form video experience solely focused around music.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Samples feed leverages YouTube&#8217;s catalog of official music videos and live footage to power the feed. Instead of simply swiping through countless songs, the feed also encourages users to interact with the song and click through to watch an entire music video or recording of a live performance. So, in other words, YouTube Music is using short-form video clips to promote the discovery of long-form video content on the platform, while also helping users discover new music.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_2582409" style="width: 610px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2582409" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-2582409" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/youtubemusic-smaples-feed.png" alt="" width="600" height="604" srcset="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/youtubemusic-smaples-feed.png 1100w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/youtubemusic-smaples-feed.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/youtubemusic-smaples-feed.png?resize=298,300 298w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/youtubemusic-smaples-feed.png?resize=768,774 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/youtubemusic-smaples-feed.png?resize=675,680 675w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/youtubemusic-smaples-feed.png?resize=32,32 32w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/youtubemusic-smaples-feed.png?resize=50,50 50w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/youtubemusic-smaples-feed.png?resize=64,64 64w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/youtubemusic-smaples-feed.png?resize=96,96 96w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/youtubemusic-smaples-feed.png?resize=128,128 128w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /><p id="caption-attachment-2582409" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Image Credits:</strong> YouTube</p></div></p>
<p>When swiping through the feed, users can add a song to their collection, share it with others, create a playlist, visit the album page, kick off a new radio station or use the song to create a Short.</p>
<p>&#8220;The feed is sort of an all-encompassing collection of related music to your tastes,&#8221; Bilinski said. &#8220;The focus is on discovery, but based on what you listen to. It&#8217;s pretty diverse, as long as the user&#8217;s tastes are diverse. And then we also want to show you stuff you haven&#8217;t seen before or listened to before. We will also show you some videos from music you&#8217;ve listened to before if you haven&#8217;t seen the video.&#8221;</p><div class="piano-inline-promo"></div>
<p><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;">The launch of the new feed is similar to the TikTok-style discovery feeds that </span><a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;" href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/03/08/spotify-revamps-its-app-with-tiktok-style-discovery-feeds-smart-shuffle-for-playlists-and-more/">Spotify rolled out</a><span style="font-size: 1rem; letter-spacing: -0.1px;"> earlier this year. The feeds allow users to preview an album, playlist or single by combining a track&#8217;s audio with video. The concept behind both YouTube Music and Spotify&#8217;s feeds is discovery through a visual aspect in a way that borrows from TikTok&#8217;s popular format. </span></p>
<p>When asked if YouTube Music plans to launch additional video feeds, Bilinski said the company is investigating it as a next step, but noted that YouTube Music wanted to start with a broad and simple feed first before rolling out more. YouTube Music plans to explore how this type of short-form discovery can be incorporated in other parts of the app and look to roll out new experiences that make it easy to discover new artists and their music.</p>
<p>The new Samples tab is beginning to roll out today to YouTube Music users on both iOS and Android globally.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/15/youtube-music-adding-tiktok-style-samples-short-form-video-feed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
